your mission at the moment to myth bust
你目前的任务是揭穿
relates to Health Care let's get into
与医疗保健相关的谣言和虚假信息，我们来深入探讨一下。
that okay Dr Mike verski he's the
好的，迈克·维尔斯基医生，他是一位
actively practicing medicine doctor with
活跃的执业医生，拥有
over 25 million followers who's created
超过2500万粉丝，并创建了
Platforms in the world Dr Mike what's
世界上最大的健康教育平台之一。迈克医生，
the key to finding a diet that's going
找到一种能够坚持下去的饮食的关键是什么？
you need to think about one calories in
你需要考虑两件真正重要的事情：第一，摄入
and calories out is true second and this
和消耗的卡路里是正确的；第二，这一点很
is important you need to have what about
重要，你需要考虑
the prevailing narrative that if you
目前流行的说法，即如果你
want to lose weight you got to get on a
想减肥就必须进行高强度运动，而
running machine nutrition that's where
营养才是
the majority of the change will come
改变的主要来源。
from what's the Medical Advantage if I
如果我每天都去健身房，那么它有什么医疗优势呢？
everything else is vaping dangerous yes
其他一切都是危险的，是的，
and no one knows this by the way this is
而且没有人知道这一点。顺便说一句，这就是
why I do what I do but the more
我这样做的原因。但更
dangerous part of it is what's your p on
危险的是，你对补充剂的看法是什么？
supplements they will make you skip on
它们会让你忽略对
doing things that are healthy for you
你有益的事情，
and supplements have side effects you
而且补充剂有副作用，
have too many of them we notice that
我们注意到它们有很多副作用，
they but no one talks about that because
但没有人谈论这一点，因为
you can't really sell that and then
你无法真正推销它们。
considering you care so much about your
考虑到你关心…… 关于你的
health why would a doctor to choose
健康，为什么医生会选择
boxing cuz I unfortunately lost my mom
拳击？因为我不幸失去了我的母亲，她
to cancer to ask the doctors to stop
死于癌症。我曾请求医生停止
doing chest compressions on your mom
对我的母亲进行胸外按压，
that is not something that I wish on
这不是我希望
anyone and I got into a very unhealthy
任何人经历的事情，我的
mental state so boxing chose me instead
精神状态也因此变得非常糟糕。所以，是拳击选择了我，而不是
of me choosing boxing in the
我选择了拳击。在
circumstances that you lost your mother
你失去母亲的情况下，
where she was giv the all clear yeah did
她当时已经被告知一切正常。是的，
that experience change your perspective
那段经历是否
of the medical industry in any way
以任何方式改变了你对医疗行业的看法？
we've just hit 6 million subscribers on
我们的D.Co.频道刚刚突破了600万订阅用户。
the D Co um so me and my team would like
我和我的团队想做
to do something we've never done before
一些我们以前从未做过的事情来表达我们的
as little thank you and we're calling it
一点谢意，我们称之为“
The dire coo subscriber raffle and here
D.Co.订阅用户抽奖”。规则如下：
is how it works every episode this month
本月每期节目，
we're going to pick three current
我们将随机抽取三位现有
subscribers at random and we'll send one
订阅用户，其中一位将获得价值
of you a 1,000 voucher one of you
1000美元的代金券，一位将获得
tickets to come and watch the D behind
观看D.Co.
the scenes live with our team and one of
幕后花絮直播的门票，还有一位
you will have a 10-minute phone call
将获得与我进行10分钟电话通话的机会，可以
with me to discuss whatever you want to
讨论任何你想
talk about if you're a subscriber you're
讨论的话题。如果你是订阅用户，你就参与了
in the raffle thank you from the bottom
抽奖。谢谢大家！
of my heart for allowing me to do
衷心感谢你们让我能够做
something that me and my team love doing
我和我的团队如此热爱的事情，
so much it is the greatest honor of my
这是我一生中最大的荣幸，
lifetime and I hope it I hope it
我希望这份荣幸能够
continues uh off into the Future Let's
延续下去。接下来我们
get to the
进入
[Music]
[音乐]
episode Dr
环节。
Mike considering everything you do from
迈克医生，考虑到您所做的一切，从
your podcast to all of the content you
您的播客到您在各个
produce across your channels to the
渠道制作的所有内容，再到
stuff you do in TV everything social
您在电视节目、社交
media all of it
媒体上的所有工作，
how do you summarize the overarching
您如何概括
mission that you're on at this in this
您目前
life the mission is largely to make sure
人生阶段的总体使命？我的使命主要是确保在充斥着
misinformation my
虚假信息的海洋中，我的
patients my viewers are getting the most
病人、我的观众能够获得最
honest transparent and engaging
真实、透明和引人入胜的
information so that hopefully they can
信息，以便他们能够
for themselves and their family
为自己和
members why do you care
家人做出最佳的医疗保健决策。您为什么关心这个？
when I was a medical student I would go
当我还是医学生的时候，我走进
into rooms with patients and they would
病房，病人会
be being seen by some of the top doctors
见到一些世界顶尖的医生——
in the world I mean experts upon experts
我是说，都是经验丰富的专家，拥有丰富的资历和
credentials published work and the
发表的著作。
second the doctor would walk out after
医生讲解完
presenting all this accurate
所有准确的
evidence-based information the patient
循证信息后，病人
would look at me as the med student and
会看着我这个医学生，
say what did he say or what did she say
问：“他说了什么？”或者“她说了什么？”
and I realized that the message wasn't
我意识到，这些信息并没有真正
hitting home and I realized we need to
触动病人。 我意识到我们
do a better job as communicators in the
在
healthcare space and then I said well TV
医疗保健领域的沟通工作需要做得更好。当时我想，电视
must be the answer media training must
一定是答案，媒体培训一定
be the answer and then as I became a
是答案。后来，当我成为一名
practicing physician in my residency
执业医生，在住院医师
program I started seeing people being
培训期间，我开始看到人们受到
influenced by those TV physicians in the
电视医生的
wrong ways they would be promising
错误影响。他们承诺
Miracle solutions to any problem they
任何问题都能得到神奇的解决方案，
would be having snake oil being sold to
兜售着所谓的“灵丹妙药”。人们以为只要
to them for three easy payments of
支付三次
1999 and I said oh man not only are we
1999美元的“解决方案”，就可以不用吃药、不用接受治疗、不用改变生活方式。我当时就想，天哪，我们不仅
not great communicators but we're being
沟通能力差，而且还被那些试图在
profit in that in this Health Care space
这个医疗保健领域牟利的人所利用。
and I viewed it as a mega problem I
我认为这是一个巨大的问题。我
remember in 2017 I wrote a blog post for
记得2017年，我为美国家庭医师学会写了一篇博客文章，
physicians and I said the lack of
我说，缺乏
evidence-based Physicians Online is is
循证医学的在线医生将会
in our patients lives it's going to
对患者的生活产生巨大的影响，这将
allow misinformation to come in
导致错误信息的传播，
especially in this section I call the
尤其是在我称之为“
gray Zone where modern science doesn't
灰色地带”的领域，也就是现代科学尚未完全确立的领域。
and they're going to come in and promise
他们会针对某些医疗问题和疾病给出答案，并承诺提供
you Solutions and they're going to be
解决方案，而且他们
quite successful at it what happened
在这方面会非常成功。
three years later covid-19 pandemic
三年后，新冠疫情爆发，
misinformation pandemic people confused
虚假信息泛滥，人们感到困惑，
not knowing who to seek out for
不知道该向谁寻求
information and for some very strange
信息。出于某种非常奇怪的
reason a doctor with only 5 years of
原因，一位只有五年
experience uh after a residency was the
经验的医生（在完成住院医师培训后）成为了
number one channel on YouTube being
YouTube上观看量最高的频道，并在
people were not watching the CDC they
人们不关注疾控中心、
weren't listening to True experts in
不听取真正专家意见的时候，提供了答案。真正的专家
said they were falling for
说，人们正在轻信
misinformation online and I had to be
网络上的虚假信息。我必须到场
there to set the record straight I
澄清事实。我简直
couldn't believe that that
不敢相信会
happened for people that might not know
发生这样的事。有些人可能不知道
who you're referring to when you cite
你指的是谁，你指的
that doct doctor that is you
是你，医生。
you reach a lot of people every month
你每月触达大量受众，
you have 12 million subscribers on
在YouTube上拥有1200万订阅者，
YouTube now you have other channels with
现在你还有其他频道，在各个
across the board and that's happened in
平台上都有数百万粉丝。这一切都发生在
quite a short space of
很短的时间内。
time what is it about you that you think
你认为是什么让你在
as it relates to sort of medical
医疗
information and spotting
信息和识别虚假
disinformation I think it's not one
信息方面如此引起这么多人的共鸣？我认为这并非单一
thing much like in healthcare this would
因素造成的，就像医疗保健领域一样。
be a multifactorial situation I think
我觉得这应该是一个多因素共同作用的结果。
when I first started the reason why I
我最初
got popularity was because I was an
走红的原因是因为我是
early adopter of Instagram and I would
Instagram的早期用户，我会
share my medical Journey uh of being a
分享我的医学之路，也就是我作为一
med student mostly because I wanted to
名医学生的经历。我主要是想
show people that you can have a life a
告诉大家，你可以拥有生活、
social life a family life a sports life
社交生活、家庭生活、运动生活，同时
and still go through medical school
还能完成医学院的学业。
because I felt like there existed this
因为我感觉社会上存在一种
stigma you have to give up everything to
刻板印象，认为学医就必须放弃一切。在
study medicine and while I was doing
我分享这些内容的同时，
that I got some followers on Instagram
我的Instagram也积累了一些粉丝。
and at that point having 10,000
在那个年代，拥有1万
followers was a huge win because it was
粉丝对我来说是一个巨大的成就，因为Instagram当时
so new and being a broke medical student
还很新。作为一个囊中羞涩的医学生，
to go to a club and say oh my God I have
去夜店说“天哪，我有
10,000 followers let me in without
1万粉丝，不用付门票就让我进去吧”，这简直太棒了。
years later I'm in my residency program
几年后，我开始住院医师培训，
BuzzFeed writes an article and they
BuzzFeed写了一篇文章。他们
didn't write an article about me being
没有写我是
the youngest doctor in my hospital they
医院里最年轻的医生，
didn't write about the fact that I was
没有写我做过一些医学研究，也没有写我
passionate about putting out accurate
热衷于发布准确的
info they the title of the article was
信息，他们的标题是…… 那篇文章的标题是“
you got check out this sexy doctor and
快来看看这位性感医生和
his awesome dog and I'm like oh that's
他超棒的狗狗”，我当时想，哦，这太
silly no one's going to read this I
傻了，没人会看的。我
thought it was cute I'd send it to some
觉得挺可爱的，就发给几个
friends and then boom that was the
朋友。结果，砰！这篇文章就火了，
seemed like every Outlet in the world
好像全世界的媒体都在
was reaching out and when I say in the
联系我。我说
world I'm not exaggerating like Outlets
全世界可不是夸张，英国的媒体、
from Budapest from Asia from the every
布达佩斯的媒体、亚洲的媒体，还有美国本土所有
possible Outlet here in the United
媒体都
States was calling for an interview and
在打电话来采访我。
I very vividly remember all the talk
我清楚地记得，所有
show hosts were reaching out and I had
脱口秀主持人都联系了我。我之前完全
no idea about this world that there
不知道这个圈子
existed so much competition where I
竞争这么激烈。我
remember the Ellen degenerous show folks
记得艾伦·德杰尼勒斯秀的人联系
reached out and they said if you do our
我说，如果你上他们的
show you can't do the Steve Harvey Show
节目，就不能上史蒂夫·哈维秀了。
and Steve Harvey reached out and said
史蒂夫·哈维也联系我说，
you know if you do our show you can't do
如果你上他们的节目，就不能上
their show I talked to some friends I'm
他们的节目了。我跟几个朋友聊了聊，我说，
like all right I'll do the own
好吧，那我上艾伦·德杰尼勒斯
degenerous show I think that'll be a
秀吧，我觉得这是个
cool opportunity and they do the
很棒的机会。他们安排了
pre-interviews I meet with the producers
预面试，我跟制片人见了面，然后
I tell them about what I'm passionate
告诉他们…… 我跟他们聊起我热衷的事情，结果在
about and the day before filming they
录制前一天，他们
call and they say hey we have some news
打电话来说：“嘿，我们有个消息，
Hillary Clinton is announcing her bid
希拉里·克林顿宣布竞选
for the presidency of the United States
美国总统，
and she's doing our daytime talk show as
她将作为第一个嘉宾参加我们的日间脱口秀节目。
the first talk show and like the other
其他
guests were like pink and Jimmy Kimmel
嘉宾还有Pink和吉米·坎摩尔，
so you're the one getting kicked off and
所以你被踢出局了。”
I said no biggie I'll go on Steve Harvey
我说：“没关系，我可以去史蒂夫·哈维的节目。”
so I called Steve Harvey's people back
于是我又给史蒂夫·哈维的团队打了电话，
and they said oh no that was two weeks
他们说：“哦，不行，那是两周前的事了，
ago we're not interested anymore and it
我们现在不感兴趣了。”这真是
was such a wakeup call where the 15
当头棒喝，原来“
minutes of fame statement was true you
昙花一现”的说法是真的。你曾经红过
were hot for a second people were
一小会儿，人们
interested about this unique story and
对这个独特的故事很感兴趣，
then they move on but I said no way I I
然后他们就转移了注意力。但我说：“不行，我
still have to push this because I viewed
还要继续努力，因为我认为
it as an opportunity to get people to
这是一个让人们
care about the
关注这些
information but drawing their attention
信息的机会，但首先要把他们的注意力引
to something else first if you look at
到其他事情上。如果你看看
who's successful in media 20 years ago
20年前在媒体上成功的那些人，
uh in the healthcare space it would be
尤其是在医疗保健领域，
unfortunately people who corrupted the
不幸的是，往往是那些为了吸引观众而歪曲
health information for the
健康信息的人。
viewership and it feels like you often
感觉很多
times have to corrupt something to get
时候，你必须歪曲某些东西才能获得关注。”
views and I felt that if I could corrupt
我当时的想法是，如果我能用一些吸引眼球的方式让
and have people come for the scandal of
人们因为“性感医生”的丑闻而来，
sexy doctor but when they come for that
但当他们真的因为这个原因而来时，
I instead give them some accurate
我却给他们提供一些准确的
information or maybe have them come for
信息，或者让他们觉得我有点
some comedy and give them some health
搞笑，同时提供一些健康
information that was a way to get people
知识，这就能吸引他们的
interested because if we're being honest
兴趣。因为说实话，如果
it can be boring if you're not
你对医疗信息、教科书和科学没有热情，它们可能会很枯燥。
passionate about it but if you can
但如果你能像
amazing teachers that I've had over the
我这些年来遇到的那些优秀的老师一样，用一种
years in a way where it's fun it's
有趣、
engaging they make it um almost like a
引人入胜的方式来呈现它们，他们会让学习变成一段
journey that you're going on suddenly
旅程，让你突然间集中
you pay attention you have a few
注意力，有所收获，
takeaways and then from those takeaways
然后
you're better equipped to handle some of
你就能更好地应对生活中
the things that could come up with it
可能遇到的各种情况。
during life and I really took that to
我一
heart in the beginning and over the last
开始就把这一点牢记在心，在过去的
five years I've really studied what
五年里，我认真研究了
marketers have done so well in the
营销人员在
commercial space or what those snake
商业领域取得的成功，以及那些
oils salesmen have done so well in
江湖骗子在
pitching their misinformation and take
兜售虚假信息方面取得的成功，
those same principles but bring them to
并将这些原则运用到
evidence-based medicine allow people to
循证医学中，让人们在
have fun while they're learning there's
学习的同时享受乐趣。这其中蕴含着
a lot of information out there as it
很多价值。 在浩如烟海的
relates to health what is your sort of
健康信息中，您是如何
framework for deciding what you share
决定分享哪些信息
and how you share it when there's so
以及如何分享的？
many a lot of these studies as well the
这类研究数量庞大，而且
the methodology of the studies is often
研究方法往往
hard to trust because of the way that
难以令人信服，因为
that you know certain studies where they
有些研究并
look at kind of they don't
没有单独
isolate one variable so you look you
考察某个变量。所以，当你查看
look at the study and it could be
研究时，你会发现他们说的可能五花八门。比如，你
anything they say you know they you hear
听说过一些
these studies about like veganism for
关于素食主义的研究，他们说
example where they say veganism is is
素食主义更
healthier but that doesn't remove out
健康，但这并不能排除
all the other factors in that person's
个人生活方式中的其他因素。也许他们
they're eating less meat but it's
吃的肉少了，但
processed meat that they're having with
他们吃的却是加工肉，比如
fries and hamburgers Etc so how do you
薯条、汉堡等等。那么，在信息海洋中，您是如何
what's your framework for deciding if
判断
something is true in a SP in a sea of
某个信息是否真实的呢？
information every time I look at some
每次看到
new
新的
research I
研究，我的
treat it differently than most people
处理方式都与大多数媒体人士不同，
would in the media space and I also
也与
treat it differently than an individual
个人不同。
would treat it so if you're a news
如果你是一家新闻
outlet and a breakthrough study comes
媒体，当一项突破性研究
out they treat it like it's the answer
发表时，他们会把它当作解决
to people's problems like it's the new
人们所有问题的答案。 这是最新的
and best I take that research and I
、最好的研究成果。我会将这些研究成果
apply it to the existing data and
应用到我多年来通过医学教育获得的现有数据和
knowledge that I've gotten over the
知识中，并将
position it in where it belongs so some
其置于恰当的位置。有些
research comes out it might make me lean
研究可能会让我倾向于
in saying we need to move closer to a
说我们需要更接近以
plant focused diet it doesn't mean that
植物为主的饮食，但这并不意味着
everyone needs to be on it doesn't mean
每个人都需要这样做，也不意味着
we need to eliminate everything because
我们需要完全摒弃所有食物。因为
in medicine extremes are rarely right
在医学领域，极端做法很少是正确的，
even when we're talking about
即使我们谈论的是
optimization you'll hear oftentimes
优化。你经常会听到
people say oh you can boost your immune
有人说，你可以增强免疫
system you could hyper optimize this no
系统，你可以过度优化这个。不，
no no hyper optimization is Extreme
不，不，过度优化是极端做法。
whenever you're going to those extremes
当你走向极端时，
you start creating problems because
就会开始制造问题，因为
that's how the human body works it works
人体就是这样运作的。人体依靠
in homeostasis it wants to be balanced
体内平衡来运作，它渴望保持平衡，
and the enemy of balance is bad but also
而平衡的敌人是有害的，但
perfect so what do you make of this
完美也是有害的。那么，你如何看待过去几年兴起的这种
optimization longevity anti-aging live
优化、长寿、抗衰老、
forever culture that's emerged in the
永生的文化呢？
last couple years I understand where
我理解
it's coming from uh We've made a lot of
它的由来。我们取得了许多
scientific progress we believe that we
科学进步，我们相信我们
should have the answers to the one
应该能够找到解决
problem that is facing all of us and
我们所有人面临的一个问题的答案，那就是
that's that life is not forever but I
生命并非永恒。 我
feel like the field has been
觉得这个领域已经被
corrupted and it's actually the way that
腐蚀了，实际上
healthc care has been corrupted across
整个医疗保健行业都受到了腐蚀。
the board so when we talk about health
当我们谈到医疗
insurance the Pharma
保险、制药
industry anti-aging industry a lot of it
业、抗衰老产业时，很多都已经被
corrupted with capitalism and I take and
资本主义腐蚀了。我
I say that as someone who's actually Pro
作为一个支持资本主义的人，也这样说，
capitalism but I believe Healthcare is a
但我认为医疗保健是一种
commodity that cannot be
无法
lift I love the idea of being able to
提倡的商品。我喜欢按需选择的想法，但这在医疗
work for healthcare you demanding what
保健领域行不通。
you want for your body when you're not
如果你不是
the expert doesn't always yield the best
专家，却要求医生给你治疗，这并不总是能带来最佳
results we've seen that time and time
效果。我们已经一次又一次地
again I see it with my patients when
看到这一点。我的病人
they come in and it's very clear that
就诊时，很明显
they have a viral Illness but they
他们得了病毒性疾病，但他们却
demand
要求开
antibiotics or they demand uh a
抗生素，或者要求开一种能让
medication that's going to help them
他们
longer doesn't exist we don't have yet
延年益寿的药物。这种药根本不存在，我们还没有足够的
the evidence to sell these things to
证据来向人们推销或解释这些药物。
people to explain them to people but
但总会
there will always be a person who will
有人
take some new information some
抓住一些新信息，一些
preliminary data data from an animal
初步数据，一些来自动物
model from a petri dish and sell it as
模型或培养皿的数据，然后把它吹捧成下一个
the next great thing this happened with
伟大的发明。
the Fountain of Youth this happened with
青春之泉就是个例子。
literally snake oil hundreds of years
几百年前，假药泛滥成灾，
ago and now it's happening but with the
如今这种情况再次发生。但
power of social media and the fact that
社交媒体的力量，以及
this misinformation a lot of times is
这些虚假信息往往具有的隐蔽性，使得
Insidious you don't realize that it's so
人们难以意识到其
bad and so problematic because what it's
危害之大。因为它
doing is it's actually tricking people
实际上是在欺骗人们，让他们
into not understanding how science Works
不了解科学的运作方式。
how when we put out a hypothesis an idea
当我们提出一个假设，即
of what we think could happen we
我们认为可能发生的事情时，我们实际上会
actually strive to disprove our
努力去证伪它。
hypothesis so if I say this glass of
所以，如果我说这
water here will help you live longer I
杯水能让你更长寿，
will actually as a scientist want to set
作为一名科学家，我实际上会努力证明
out to prove that it doesn't and I will
它无效。我会想尽一切办法，甚至会找
people to disagree with me and find ways
人来反驳我的观点，寻找各种方法来
that we could test that this doesn't
验证它是否
work but right now on social media what
有效。但现在在社交媒体上，
you see is a lot of people just
我们看到的是很多人只
supporting what agrees with them what
支持那些与自己观点一致的信息。那么，在
proliferated across social media that
社交媒体上流传的哪些观点
irritate you the most and you think are
最让你感到恼火，你认为它们
most harmful I think the ones that
最有害呢？我认为是那些在充满不
create certainty in an uncertain world
确定性的世界中制造确定性的观点。
and I think that could apply to pretty
我认为这几乎适用于
much any field I talked about the gray
任何领域。我之前提到过“灰色
Zone earlier and I think the gray Zone
地带”，我认为“灰色地带”
has
已经发生了
changed 30 years ago the gray Zone was
变化。  30年前，减肥还处于灰色地带。
weight loss yeah and if you put on any
没错，如果你打开任何一个
TV channel especially late at night
电视频道，尤其是在深夜，你会看到各种
there would be a fat burner there'd be
减肥产品，比如
some grapefruit diet or some next great
葡萄柚减肥法，或者其他什么所谓的“新奇减肥
thing that someone came up with but
方法”。但
everyone forgets about all that people
大家都忘了，过去人们
used to sell you nonsense to try and
兜售的都是些不靠谱的减肥产品，试图
help you lose weight and all of it
帮你减肥，结果全都无效，而且
didn't work it was not healthy even if
不健康。即使
it made you lose weight it was in an
能让你瘦下来，也是以
unhealthy way it ended up creating and
不健康的方式。最终，它们反而让
cycle for most folks and then came out
大多数人陷入了类似饮食失调的恶性循环。后来，
some medic s like
像
OIC and people started actually losing
OIC这样的药物出现了，人们开始使用
weight with an FDA approved medicine
FDA批准的、真正有效的减肥药来减肥。
that had Real Results now you see less
现在，你看到的
of those fat burner ads but you see more
减肥产品广告少了，但更多的是
of a new Gray Zone
新的灰色地带——
anti-aging science doesn't have an
抗衰老。科学无法
answer to stop us from aging we don't
阻止衰老，我们无法
have the answers perfectly to our
完全了解我们的
genetic code but boy there will be a
基因密码。但肯定会有
genetic test for sale that will tell you
基因检测产品上市，告诉你
exactly what you need to avoid but the
应该避免什么。但
reality is we just don't know and it's
现实是，我们真的不知道。
not sexy to say I don't know but I've
承认自己不知道并不光彩，但我
been passionate about encouraging folks
一直热衷于鼓励大家
to celebrate those experts who come in
去欣赏那些专家。 进来，
and say here's what we don't know but
告诉我们我们不知道的事情，以及
here's how we're working to get to those
我们正在如何努力寻找
answers because that's what gets me
答案，因为这才是让我
excited there's so many breakthroughs
兴奋的地方。医学领域正在取得许多突破，
being made in medicine and we don't talk
但我们很少谈论
about those honest breakthroughs because
这些真正的突破，因为
they're not always exciting but if we
它们并不总是令人兴奋。但如果我们
could pair it with something cultural if
能将它们与文化结合起来，如果
we could pair it with some comedy with
能与一些喜剧和
some fun I think we can get in front of
趣味结合起来，我认为我们就能吸引
a lot of eyes one of the first things
更多人的目光。
you said there was was about weight loss
你首先提到的是关于减肥的话题，
in a zmek and it's
这是
a incredibly relevant and
一个目前非常热门且被
um widely discussed subject at the
广泛讨论的话题。
moment as zmek I I listen to the
作为减肥专家，我关注着相关的
research on a zek and I am someone that
研究，我
typically has a bias towards not taking
通常倾向于尽可能避免服用
medications if I can and pursuing a
药物，而是选择
natural route and and that is what we do
自然疗法。这也是我们所做的，是的，这
too yeah which is understated in most uh
在大多数
as doctors yeah yeah so our training for
医生圈子里都被低估了。例如，我们的培训中
example if you look at our we have a
有一个
reference called let's say up toate it's
参考资料，叫做UpToDate，这是
a medical platform where we could go and
一个医疗平台，我们可以从中
get guidance on any medical condition
获得任何疾病的指导，
and it could tell us what the
它可以告诉我们流行病学情况以及哪些人更容易患上这种
epidemiology is who gets sick with it uh
疾病。 生病了，
what is the diagnosis that we should do
我们应该如何诊断？
Testing what Imaging we should do uh
应该做哪些实验室检查？影像学检查？
What treatments work first line Second
哪些治疗方案有效？一线、
Line third line Etc if we look at pretty
二线、三线等等。如果我们看一下
much any crime disease treatment whether
几乎所有疾病的治疗，无论是
it's high blood pressure um sugar
高血压还是糖尿病等血糖
management from like
控制，
diabetes all of the first steps is
第一步都是
lifestyle
生活方式的
modifications that's what we're taught
改变。这是我们从小接受的教育，
is that because of the type of training
因为
you had doctor you became or is that all
你接受的培训类型决定了你成为医生，或者所有
medical doctors that is all medical
医生都是如此？是的，所有
doctors but what ends up happening is
医生都是如此。但最终的结果有
twofold
两个方面：
one patients love a
一是患者喜欢
shortcut they love having a medication
走捷径，他们喜欢药物
potentially do the work that they may
可以代替他们可能无法
not be able to or don't want to you know
或不想做的
changes but then there's a portion of us
改变。这里很难一概而论，因为有些患者的生活确实很艰难，他们可能身兼三职，是单亲父母，或者正经历精神健康危机，所以他们可能无法做出这些生活方式的改变。但也有一部分人
who could do it but prefer to take the
能够做到，却更倾向于
shortcut and that's pretty human of us
走捷径，这很人性化，我们都想
we we would like to get the shortcut we
走捷径，我们都想
would like to take the edge is there
占上风。
such a thing as a shortcut in healthcare
医疗保健中真的存在捷径吗？
no and I heard you actually say it on
没有。 我听你在上
your last podcast uh covering OIC that
一期播客里也说过，关于OIC（口服补液盐），
there is no shortcut there are side
没有捷径可走，任何事情都有
effects and trade-offs to everything and
副作用和权衡取舍。
you're absolutely right in that there is
你说得完全正确，没有什么东西是万无一失的。补水，
hydration you can't live without it over
不喝水就活不下去；喝太多会
drink you'll throw off your electrolytes
扰乱电解质平衡，
you could damage your brain you could
可能损伤大脑，甚至
lose your life carrots healthy food I
危及生命。胡萝卜是健康食品，我
would say eat enough you'll turn
建议多吃，不然会
orange same thing goes for medications
变黄。药物也是如此。这就是
and that's why when people go and
为什么人们会
villainize treatments
妖魔化治疗、药物和
medications supplements it just depends
补充剂的原因。这要视情况而定，
and there needs to be Nuance it's too
需要细致分析。不能
hard to paint medicine with a broad
一概而论地看待医学，
brush but social media makes that really
但社交媒体让这种做法变得非常
tempting that that non aemp path if I'm
诱人。如果我
not going to take the the new sort of
不服用那些新型的
fat burning magic pills or the appetite
燃脂神奇药丸或
I guess I guess they suppress appetite
抑制食欲的
um magic pills
神奇药丸，那么非药物治疗就
that becomes another a bit of still is a
成了另一个
bit of a gray area in many respects
灰色地带。
because we on the drug side of things
因为在药物方面，
people now have an option that's FDA
人们现在有了FDA
approved but if they don't want to
批准的选择，但如果他们
pursue that path there's still all of
不想走这条路，还有其他选择。
this other information around okay I
关于减肥的信息很多，
opportunity for a lot of people to
很多人都想
present them with Solutions there's a
提供解决方案，但
there's a roaring debate around calories
关于卡路里的争论却一直
which seems to just be never ending and
没完没了。
um I wanted to get your take on that if
我想听听你的看法。
if someone was you know in your training
如果你接受过相关培训，有人
when you've been advised to suggest
建议你
Lifestyle Changes first and foremost if
首先建议他们改变生活方式，比如，如果
I'm trying to lose a bit of weight I'm
我想减肥，但又
you know at risk of being diabetic or
担心自己有患糖尿病或
something what would you say to me as
其他疾病的风险，你会怎么做？ 作为一名患者，你会对我说什么？
patient it would be hard to generalize
很难一概而论，
it because it really depends on what
因为这真的取决于你
pre-existing conditions exist what have
既往的健康状况、你
you tried thus far what works what do
目前尝试过哪些方法、哪些方法有效、
you have time for what do you have
你有哪些时间、你的
budget for on that point of tried thus
预算。关于你目前尝试过的方法，为什么会这样？
far why is that why does that matter so
为什么这一点如此重要？
much if I have a patient who's tried
如果我的患者尝试过
dieting
节食
and
但
failed and I don't ask that question and
失败了，而我没有问这个问题，只是
I recommend
建议他们节食，
dieting they may not take the advice
他们可能不会接受我的建议。他们可能会点
they may nod because they want to be a
点头，因为他们想做一个“
quote unquote good patient and leave and
好病人”，然后离开并
say not doing it but if I ask that
说他们不会节食。但如果我问了这个
question they can say they tried and
问题，他们就可以告诉我他们尝试过但
failed then that gives me an opportunity
失败了，这让我有机会
to ask what exactly did they try did
询问他们具体尝试了什么。
they try some really restrictive diet
他们是否尝试过一些非常严格的饮食，比如纯肉饮食、
that's out there carnivore keto what
生酮饮食等等，而这些饮食方式最终导致
have you and that set them up for fail
失败，因为它们
something that wasn't able to be
无法长期
sustainable whereas now I can explain
坚持？现在我可以解释
that hey the thing you tried actually
说，你尝试的方法实际上导致了
set you up for failure and here's a more
失败，这里有一个更
reasonable recommendation that we can
合理的建议，我们可以
try and now I can actually be a doctor
尝试一下。现在我才能真正成为一名医生，
that recommends a dietary modification
推荐一种可能对他们有帮助的饮食调整方案。
finding a diet that is successful from
找到一种成功的饮食的关键是什么？
your experience what are the like the
你的经验是，那种能让节食坚持下去的
foundational factors of that diet that's
饮食基础因素是什么？
about when it comes to dieting one
说到节食，你需要考虑两件事：一是
is its impact on your weight because
它对体重的影响，因为
calories in and calories out as non-sexy
摄入的卡路里和消耗的卡路里之间的平衡——
as it sounds as clinical and cold and
虽然听起来很枯燥，甚至冷酷无情，但这是
true second you also need to think about
事实；二是
the nutrients in your food because if we
食物中的营养成分，因为如果我们
just take one of those parts and ignore
只关注其中一方面而忽略
the other we can get into a really bad
另一方面，就会陷入非常糟糕的
place I can uh even see those grapefruit
境地。我甚至见过一些所谓的“葡萄柚
diets that people say like eat three
减肥法”，比如每天吃三个
grap fruits a day and you'll lose weight
葡萄柚就能减肥——
yeah you will because you're underc
没错，你的确会瘦下来，因为你
consuming calories but is that healthy
摄入的卡路里不足。但从
from a nutrition side absolutely not on
营养角度来看，这健康吗？绝对不健康。
the other side is you can get enough
另一方面，即使你摄入了足够的
protein enough nutrients but if you're
蛋白质和其他营养，如果
overeating calories you can get into a
卡路里摄入过量，也会导致
metabolic problem where now you're
代谢问题，导致
carrying excess weight and increasing
体重超标，并增加
your risks of all sorts of conditions so
患各种疾病的风险。所以，
the goal is to get you in a place where
目标是让你的饮食达到
it's balanced in both a caloric weight
平衡，既要控制卡路里摄入，
management standpoint but also an
又要保持
ideally a healthy nutritional balance as
理想的营养平衡。那么，
well well and what that means personto
这意味着什么呢？ 每个
person is going to vary it's going to
人的情况都不一样，这
vary based on the medical condition they
取决于他们的健康状况。
have some patients who are anemic may
有些贫血患者可能
need certain nutrients that someone
需要某些营养素，而非
who's not anemic doesn't need someone
贫血患者则不需要。容易患肾结石的人
who's prone to kidney stones may need a
可能需要与
is IBS prone so we need to always take
易患肠易激综合征（IBS）的人略有不同的饮食。因此，我们需要始终
into account that generalized advice
记住，在医疗保健方面，笼统的建议
isn't great when it comes to Health Care
并不理想，
especially when it's very easy to create
尤其是在很容易从健康真相中炮制出一些
Buzzy statements from truth
耸人听闻的说法的时候。
in healthare like I said on a podcast
就像我不久前在播客里说的那样，
not too long ago that exercise for
运动对
weight loss Almost Doesn't Matter and
减肥几乎无关紧要。
that's a buzzy statement because on one
这之所以引人注目，是因为一方面
hand it's true but you also need to pair
它是正确的，但另一方面，你也需要结合
it with some nuance and say exercise has
一些细微差别来理解它，比如运动
so many benefits outside of weight loss
除了减肥之外还有很多其他益处，这才是
of why it's important to participate in
参与运动的重要性所在。
exercise and the idea of weight loss
减肥的理念
needs to come from
应该源于营养，
nutrition that's where the majority of
大部分的
the change will come from Super
改变都将来自营养。这很
interesting cuz I've sat here with so
有意思，因为我曾和
many people that have said that to me um
很多人讨论过这个问题。
they've said that when you look at a lot
他们说，当你查看很多
of the studies exercise as a if you if
研究时，你会发现，如果
you give prescribe someone exercise to
你给别人开运动处方来
lose weight they probably won't lose
减肥，运动就显得不那么重要了。 他们可能不会
weight um but I would definitely say
减肥，嗯，但我肯定地说，
that in culture people see exercise as
在文化上，人们看待运动的方式和
the many would see I reckon the primary
很多人一样，我认为运动是
way you lose weight they think you have
减肥的主要途径。他们认为你必须
to go for a run to lose weight and and
跑步才能减肥，
again you've Express the Nuance there
你刚才表达的细微差别我也很
but I've even I've struggled with
困惑，
understanding that because over here
因为即使在这里，
people say exercise isn't super useful
人们也说研究表明运动对减肥并没有太大帮助，
for weight loss in the studies but then
但
the the prevailing narrative in society
社会上普遍的说法
is that if you want to lose weight you
是，如果你想减肥就
got to get on a running machine that's
必须使用跑步机。这是
because they're equating in their
因为他们把
minds Health with a magazine
健康等同于杂志
cover and health is not a magazine
封面，而健康并非杂志
cover they think that you need to have
封面。他们认为你需要拥有
big muscles to be considered healthy and
健硕的肌肉才算健康，
while you can have big muscles and be
虽然你可以拥有健硕的肌肉并保持
healthy you could have big muscles and
健康，但你也可能拥有健硕的肌肉却
be tremendously unhealthy so just
非常不健康。所以，仅仅
looking at someone's appearance doesn't
观察一个人的外表并不能让
give you the full picture just like
你了解全貌，就像
looking at someone's weight doesn't give
观察一个人的体重也不能让
you the full picture you need to know
你了解全貌一样，你需要了解
more and when it comes to exercise and
更多信息。说到运动和
weight loss let's just take for a very
减肥，我们举一个非常
simple example I used to go to the
简单的例子：我小时候经常去看
movies when I was a kid I loved it I did
电影，我很喜欢看电影。 我一直都这么做，
it all the time it is not unusual to eat
吃
a tub of popcorn a little candy bar and
一大桶爆米花、一小块巧克力和一瓶
a soda well over over 1,000 calories do
汽水，一口气摄入超过1000卡路里，这并不罕见。
you know how hard it is through exercise
你知道通过运动消耗掉这1000卡路里有多难吗？
calories most of us are not physically
我们大多数人的身体条件
even equipped to burn a th000 calories
甚至都无法在一次运动中消耗掉这么多卡路里。
during an exercise session so it's just
所以，这完全是
about the science of not being able to
科学原理决定的，
out exercise a bad diet what if I just
运动无法弥补不良饮食带来的负面影响。如果我
eat loads of salads I think I've been in
多吃沙拉呢？我想我
that mindset before where I thought well
以前也有过这种想法，觉得“
I it's just really I could
我本来可以……”。我
life where I've just just eaten more and
人生中也曾有过一段时间，吃了很多“
more and more good stuff quotequote good
好东西”，一些
stuff things that I thought were good um
我认为很好的东西，
but I also didn't lose
但我并没有
weight you are you're a really smart
减肥。你很聪明，你
person you're a person that wants to be
希望
as effective as you can in your podcast
在你的播客和
in your communication style and you're
沟通方式中做到尽善尽美，而且你在这方面做得非常
amazing at it you want to do the same
出色。你也想在饮食方面做到同样出色。但是，
tricks that you use in your business
你在商业
mind in your communication mind don't
思维和沟通思维中使用的那些技巧和窍门，在
work for healthcare you cannot find the
医疗保健领域并不适用。 别指望找到能
fix everything that bothers you of the
解决你所有问题的沙拉捷径，也别指望
probiotic Miracle supplement it's not
益生菌之类的神奇补充剂能​​解决你所有的问题。这就是
going to be there that's why some of the
为什么有些最容易被
the most simplest forms of
最简单的
misinformation are those who are really
错误信息误导的人，恰恰是那些非常
good at
擅长
business because the things that work
经商的人。因为
very well in the business world and the
在商业和
communication space don't work in
沟通领域行之有效的方法，在医疗
healthcare because Healthcare is not a
保健领域却行不通。医疗保健不是一种
commodity healthare does not work well
商品，它不适合
with extremes you cannot do something so
走极端。你不可能一直做到
good all the time without it having
完美而不产生
negative repercussions you want to be
负面影响。在医疗保健方面，你想要的是
good not perfect when it comes to
好，而不是完美。
healthare and the more you try and Chase
你越是追求完美，首先你会
perfect number one you're going to get
得到
the negative response but also number
负面反馈，其次
two you're going to create anxieties
你会制造焦虑和担忧，而这些焦虑和担忧
worries that are also toxic to your
对你的
body you have to be very careful so
身体有害。你必须非常小心。所以，
perfect is not only Just an Illusion
完美不仅是一种幻觉，而且
it's a toxic
是一种有害的
illusion I saw someone talking recently
幻觉。我最近看到有人在讨论“
about the calories in calories out thing
摄入卡路里-消耗卡路里”这个概念，
and the first comment was a lady who I
第一个评论是一位女士，我
think had a pre-existing condition
猜她可能患有某种疾病。她
basically saying because my because of
基本上是说，因为
my pre-existing condition the calories
我的疾病，“
in calories out thing does not work for
摄入卡路里-消耗卡路里”这个概念对我无效。 对
me I've tried it and then the health
我来说没用，我试过了。然后那位健康
influencer responded and said it works
博主回应说，这方法
for
对
everybody both statements are true okay
每个人都有效。两种说法都对，好吧，
dialectics are common in healthcare
辩证法在医疗保健领域很常见。
we're two opposing ideas can both be
两种对立的观点可能都
true someone can try and do calories in
成立。有人可能会尝试用“摄入卡路里-消耗
calories out which through science works
卡路里”的理论，从科学角度来看，这个理论是有效的，
but the application of it can fail well
但实际应用可能会失败。我
I'm thinking not about the application
指的是，
regardless of whether I have a
无论我是否有
pre-existing condition not
既往疾病，这个
part of the application okay the
理论都适用。既往疾病
individual is part of the application I
是应用的一部分。我
think she was making the case that
认为她想表达的是，
because of that existing condition that
由于她有既往疾病，所以这个理论的
the maths of it don't apply to her like
数学原理对她不适用，它
it doesn't actually work on her body it
实际上对她的身体
shifts versus the applic okay it
不起作用，而是发生了变化。好吧，确实会发生变化，这在
for most medicine like when I try and
大多数医学领域都是如此。比如，当我试图让
get my patients into a healthy blood
我的病人将血压控制在健康的
pressure range because we know that uh
范围内时，因为我们知道，
having a resting blood pressure above a
静息血压高于某个
certain number predisposes you to having
数值会增加
risks of heart attack stroke all these
心脏病、中风等
cardiovascular
心血管
conditions when I treat them with a
疾病的风险。当我在
medication after lifestyle changes
生活方式改变
either didn't work or they weren't able
无效或他们无法
to go down that route
坚持下去之后，我会用药物治疗他们。 从
public healthwise we know that
公共卫生的角度来看，我们知道大规模
controlling the blood pressure on a
控制血压可以显著
large scale will lower deaths
降低死亡率，显著
significantly we'll lower heart attacks
降低心脏病发作率。
significantly but by me medicating this
但是，如果我给这个
patient I have no idea if it's going to
病人用药，我并不知道这是否真的能
help this individual exactly but that's
帮助到他。这是
because all we're doing in medicine is
因为在医学领域，我们只能尽力利用我们掌握的
doing our best with the limited
有限
information that we have on
信息。
hand closing off on that point about
关于
exercise so if if we shouldn't be
运动，我们暂且不谈。如果我们不应该把
thinking about exercise as a way to lose
运动当作减肥的方法，那么运动的
weight what what is the sort of Medical
医学
Advantage the physiological Advantage
优势和生理优势是什么呢？
for me if I go to the gym every day and
如果我每天都去健身房，保持
I'm I'm active literally everything else
活跃，那么运动带来的其他所有益处，比如
Earth happiness
幸福感、良好的
mood social connections strength ability
情绪、社交关系、力量、
to decrease cancer risk decrease uh
降低患癌风险、
increase ability to fight off cancer
增强抵抗癌症的能力、
increase longevity literally everything
延长寿命等等，几乎无所不包。
else is the benefit of exercise and I
我之所以这么
say that as someone who's been very
说，是因为我一直以来都非常
exercise focused but over the last few
注重运动，但最近
months I've kind of fallen off I've
几个月我有点懈怠了，
gained some weight I haven't been
体重增加了一些，运动量也不如以前了。
exercising as much as I want because
因为
sometimes life gets hard life gets in
生活有时会很艰难，会遇到各种阻碍，
the way things become problematic mental
事情也会变得棘手，心理
health sometimes takes a struggle and we
健康问题有时也会影响到我。 这是一种挣扎，我们
need to be aware that that can happen
需要意识到这种情况可能会发生。认为
the idea that we need to make every
我们需要让每个
person perfect or if they're not perfect
人都完美，或者如果他们不完美就是
they failure that's such a dangerous
失败，这种想法非常危险，因为它会让我们
Rabbit Hole to go into how much
陷入一个危险的陷阱。至于
exercise going to vary person to person
运动量因人而异，
General guidelines say 150 minutes of
一般指南建议每周进行150分钟的
moderate intensity exercise per week
中等强度运动，这
which isn't a lot two and a half hours
并不多，大约两个半小时。
um moderate intensity meaning that you
中等强度意味着你
shouldn't be able to speak full
可能无法说出完整的
sentences maybe one sentence at a time
句子，一次只能说一句话，
until you're out of breath is a simple
直到你气喘吁吁。简单来说，就是
way to put it when you you um have such
当你对医学有如此
a broad view on medicine well I noticed
广阔的视野时，我注意到
that in your content I was like this guy
你的内容，我觉得这个人
really knows he really has a real much
真的很懂，他的
more Broad View than the neuroscientist
视野比我昨天交谈的那位神经科学家要广阔得多，那位神经科学家
focused on you know maybe one part of
可能只关注身体的某个部位。有了这种
the body with that broad view what are
广阔的视野，
you concerned about in terms of macro
你担心宏观
social trends the direction of travel
社会趋势，以及
that we're going in with our health we
我们健康发展的方向。我们
talked about misinformation and
讨论了错误信息和
disinformation but but actual realities
虚假信息，但
of the Western Health Care
西方医疗保健的实际情况是，
condition first of all I think it's
首先，我认为
important that we have both individuals
重要的是，我们要让个人
participating and having a seat at the
参与进来，让他们在
table the broad view primary care
决策中占有一席之地，同时要有广阔的视野和初级保健。
physician and the single point expert
医生和像
neuroscientist like you had on your
您
podcast before me we need both in fact
之前在播客节目中提到的那位神经科学家一样的专家，我们都需要。事实上，
where I'm able to gather my information
我获取信息的来源
from is from all those researchers that
正是那些
are putting in those hours at the bench
在实验室里投入大量时间的科研人员，他们
making sure that they're checking their
确保自己能够检验
biases showing the flaws of their own
偏见，并指出自身
research without them I am nothing right
研究的缺陷。没有他们，我什么都不知道，
like where did I get my knowledge from
我的知识从何而来？
from them so we absolutely need to do
所以，我们绝对需要以
this in a teamwork approach I think the
团队合作的方式来完成这项工作。我认为
big problem that we face today is two
我们今天面临的最大问题是两点：一是
health care world that's huge people
医疗保健领域信任的丧失，这是一个巨大的问题。人们
don't trust healthc care advice they
不信任医疗建议，
don't trust our agencies frankly the
不信任医疗机构。坦白说，
shocking over the last decade and then
过去十年里，人们对医生的信任度下降得相当惊人。
second is it's more of a philosophical
二是我提出的这个问题更多的是一个哲学
issue that I raise because I don't know
问题，因为我不知道未来会怎样。
where it's going to go where we've
我们
created this world of processed foods
创造了一个充斥着加工食品和
unhealthy Foods foods that it caus us to
不健康食品的世界，这些食品导致我们
eat more and more and more and feel not
吃得越来越多，却始终感觉不到
satiated and then we've come up with a
饱腹感。然后，我们研发出
medication to solve that we've created
药物来解决这个问题，我们开发出的
apps that pull our attention spans that
应用程序却分散了我们的注意力。 这
allow us to focus 10 15 seconds at a
让我们每次只能集中注意力10到15秒，然后再
time before we swipe to the next
滑动屏幕切换到下一个
thing now a lot of people are requesting
内容。现在很多人都在申请
prescriptions for ADHD
ADHD
medications there's people who want to
药物处方，有些人想
stay out all night and party and still
通宵派对，同时还能
maintain their physical gains they get
保持身材，他们在
on testosterone early when they don't
不需要的时候就过早地开始服用睾酮。
get as a
作为一个
society to a point
社会，我们究竟会过度依赖药物到什么程度，以至于
of actually harming us and I don't know
真正伤害到我们自己？我不知道
the answer to it I'm not smart enough to
答案，我没那么聪明
know the answer to that but I think it's
知道答案，但我认为这是
a good philosophical question to ask
一个很好的哲学问题，值得我们思考。
ourselves are you scared about what
你是否害怕
would happen if we had a pandemic that
如果出现比上次疫情致命10倍的疫情会发生什么？
previous pandemic break out now are you
你是否
scared because of that loss of trust the
因为信任的丧失而感到害怕？
more deadly the pandemic a lot of times
很多时候，疫情越致命，
the less problematic it is isn't that
问题反而越少，这不是很
weird oh okay so initial SARS virus was
奇怪吗？哦，好吧，最初的SARS病毒
significantly moread than SARS Cove 2
比SARS-CoV-2（即
which is the virus that causes covid-19
导致COVID-19的病毒）致命得多。
so initially when the reports came out
最初，当
about The lethality rate of SARS Cove 2
SARS-CoV-2的致死率报告出来时……
covid-19 we said oh well it's not as bad
新冠病毒爆发时，我们说，哦，它没SARS那么严重，
as SARS we'll be okay because most
我们会没事的，因为大多数
people with SARS got really sick they
SARS患者病情都很严重，甚至
lost their lives but because
失去了生命。但新
covid meaning that you could feel fine
冠病毒存在无症状传播，这意味着你可能感觉良好，
or maybe just have a sniffles and spread
或者只是有点感冒，但仍然会传播病毒，导致
it it killed Millions more
数百万人死亡。
people and that's what that brings me
这让我想起了
back to that point of when I said
我之前说过的：
Insidious misinformation can be more
隐蔽的错误信息可能
problematic than true
比真正的
disinformation because when something
虚假信息更成问题。因为当某些事情
doesn't seem so
看起来没那么
bad that can we can allow it to go much
糟糕时，我们可能会放任它
further and cause much more harm
进一步蔓延，造成更大的危害。
complacency can complacency and feelings
自满情绪和
of safety like oh well this one's not as
安全感会让人觉得，哦，这次没那么严重，
Hill we're good I I feel fine we're good
我们没事，我感觉很好，我们没事。
but when you look at it and you zoom out
但当你从
macro oh my God it's Wrecking Havoc
宏观的角度来看待它时，天哪，它正在全球肆虐。
and I've actually equated this to
我甚至把这种情况比作电子烟。从理论上讲，电子烟
vaping vaping is not as harmful
不如香烟有害，
paper but because the odor is not as
但由于它的气味不那么
offensive it's easier to hide you could
刺鼻，更容易隐藏，你可以
do it much quicker and get a bigger dose
更快地吸食，摄入更大的剂量。
because it feels like it's not as
感觉电子烟的危害似乎没那么大，但
harmful many more people can get hooked
很多人却会上瘾。电子
it is vaping dangerous yes
烟危险吗？是的，
why and how so many of my friends VIP I
为什么？我的很多朋友都用电子烟，
think three three out of my six best
我六个最好的朋友里有三个都用，他们简直
they're just absolutely addicted they
上瘾了，而且他们以前
never smoked interestingly that's the
从没抽过烟。有趣的是，
issue of it that it gets people who
问题就在于此，它让那些原本
maybe would have been turned off by
可能对
smoking to try and the chemicals found
香烟敬而远之的人去尝试，而且电子烟中的化学物质
inside are really rewarding to the brain
对大脑有很强的刺激作用，
nicotine being prime example of it and
尼古丁就是最典型的例子。
the more dangerous part of it is with
更危险的是，对于大脑
kids who have a developing frontal lobe
额叶尚未发育完全的儿童来说，
so they're incredibly susceptible to
他们更容易对
anything that can build a tolerance a
任何能产生耐受性、
dependence uh an addiction to and it can
依赖性甚至成瘾的物质产生影响，而且这些物质还会
change the chemistry of their brain
改变他们大脑的化学成分。
moving forward so we don't want to make
所以我们不应该让
it easier for them to start smoking
他们更容易开始抽烟。电子
vaping should be used as a tool as a way
烟应该被用作
of getting you off of cigarettes not as
戒烟的工具，而不是让
a way of introducing you to cigarettes
你接触香烟
or nicotine at
或尼古丁的途径。
if you're coming off cigarettes no it's
如果成年人也开始使用电子烟，它危险吗？ 戒烟？不，这当然是
a good choice but if you never all my
个好选择。但如果你从未吸烟，我所有抽
friends that Vape never smoked yep it's
电子烟的朋友都从未吸烟。是的，电子烟对
value healthwise and can only
健康没有益处，只会造成
potentially harm have they have they
潜在危害。他们
done any I guess it's super difficult to
做过相关研究吗？我想，
do studies on these kinds of things but
对这类事情进行研究非常困难，但
have is there any studies that have been
有没有关于电子烟的研究？是的，已经
done around vaping yeah there's been
出现过
hospitalized with it um there's been
与电子烟相关的肺损伤，现在这已经是一个独立的诊断代码了。有儿童因此住院，
even technical problems of the devices
甚至还有设备
blowing up in people's faces so it's not
爆炸伤人的技术问题。所以，
the fact that I'm trying to fearmonger
我并不是想危言耸听，
here and say vaping is the devil I'm
说电子烟是魔鬼。我只是
here trying to explain that vaping can
想解释电子烟可能
be problematic because on the surface it
存在问题，因为表面上看，它
may not look as harmful by
似乎没有那么有害。
comparison Everything is trade-offs
凡事都有利弊，
Everything is trade so interesting it's
有的弊大于利。很有意思的是，
like when I see all my friends vaping
当我看到我的朋友们都在抽电子烟时——
they're all in we're all in Dubai a
我们
couple of about a year ago and I thought
大约一年前在迪拜——我想，算
Poss me because they will have these
我一个，因为他们会用那种
little like disposable Vape things now
一次性电子烟。 现在情况就是这样，
so let me try I tried it and it was
让我试试。我试过了，感觉真的
really nice and I thought oh God I could
很好，我想，天哪，我可能会喜欢
get into this and if it's not unhealthy
上它。如果它不有害健康，
CU like we all know that smoking is
就像我们都知道吸烟有害
unhealthy I thought you know your head
健康一样，我想，你知道，
you think oh what's the harm I could
你会想，哦，有什么害处呢？我本来很
have so easily gotten to it luckily I
容易就能接触到它。幸运的是，我
just I'm always
总是对
skeptical when I don't know the side
未知的副作用持怀疑态度。
effect I I would rather accept the side
我宁愿接受
effects yeah and it be super clear than
副作用，而且要非常清楚，而不是听
to someone say say to me there's no side
人说没有
effects when someone says there's no
副作用。当有人说没有
side effects I always well that's like
副作用时，我总是觉得这是
the whole nature fallacy when someone's
自然谬误。当有人说“
like oh but this is natural natural
哦，但这很天然”时，
first of all what does that mean because
首先，天然是什么意思？因为
like they say vitamins are natural but
就像他们说维生素是天然的，但
they're made in a lab I don't know how
它们是在实验室里合成的。我不知道
that's considered natural and also just
这怎么能被认为是天然的。而且，仅仅
because something natural doesn't mean
因为某种东西是天然的并不意味着
it's safe arsenic cyanide natural but
它是安全的。砷和氰化物是天然的，但却是
deadly the ADHD point you mentioned Y
致命的。你提到的多动症，
what are you seeing as a doctor you know
作为一名医生，你看到了什么？你知道，在
over the last couple of years the the
过去的几年里，“
term ADHD neurodiversity has seems to
多动症”和“神经多样性”这两个术语似乎变得
have become more and more prevalent
越来越流行。 而且，
everywhere I look it feels like I'm
我感觉到处都在
hearing a conversation around ADHD is
谈论多动症，是
that because there's been a social sort
因为社会对
of heightened awareness to the subject
多动症的关注度提高了，
and now people are getting diagnosed
确诊人数也增加了。
more are we creating more ADHD somehow
我们是不是在某种程度上制造了更多的多动症患者？
or is it somewhere in between yeah I I
或者介于两者之间？嗯，我
assume it's something in between I don't
猜是介于两者之间，我没有
have a clear answer to it uh I do know
明确的答案。我知道
that neuro Divergence needs to be talked
神经多样性需要
about more and that's not just from the
更多地被讨论，这不仅仅是从
ADHD perspective it's also from um
多动症的角度来看，也包括
autism spectrum disorder uh situation as
自闭症谱系障碍的情况。每个
well where it's folks are going to be
人都是
different and some people want treatment
不同的，有些人想要接受治疗，有些人则
for a condition others don't and we have
不想。我们必须
to respect people's autonomy even when
尊重每个人的自主权，即使是像
we talk about something like vaping if
电子烟这样的事情。如果
an adult wants to vape as long as I can
一个成年人想吸电子烟，只要我
convey to them as their doctor the
作为医生能够向他们解释
risks everyone's free to make their own
风险，每个人都有权做出自己的
decisions no one lives a life where they
决定。没有人会
say I'm going to take no risks everyone
说“我绝对不会冒任何风险”，每个人的
has a different risk tolerance level
风险承受能力都不同，每个人对医疗护理的需求也
everyone is comfortable with a different
不同。
level of care in life some people want
有些人想要
more care some people want less care
更多的护理，有些人想要更少的护理，
even at the end of life I have
即使在生命的尽头也是如此。 我
Life Care often and a lot of times
经常和我的病人讨论临终关怀，很多时候
they're shocked by it they're like wait
他们都会感到震惊，他们会说：“等等，
do you think something's wrong with me
你觉得我有什么问题吗？
I'm 30 years old why are you talk this
我才30岁，你为什么现在就谈这个？” 你应该在
healthy when you you aren't facing a
健康的时候谈论这个，在你不用
decision that you have to make right now
立刻做出决定的时候，你才能有
spend some time and think about what
时间好好想想你
kind of medical care you want you know
想要什么样的医疗护理。你知道，
I'm a doctor here that became a
我是一名医生，
professional boxer A couple of years ago
几年前我成为了一名职业拳击手。
that is not healthy I do not recommend
这并不健康，我不推荐这样做，
it it increases all sorts of risks for
它会增加各种各样的风险，比如
head and injury chronic traumatic incopy
头部受伤、慢性创伤等等。这些都是
all of that is true it's a risk that I
事实。我
was willing to accept because I studied
愿意承担这些风险，因为我研究过这些
the risks I accepted the risks I don't
风险，我接受了这些风险，我并不
doubt the risks but it's something that
怀疑这些风险。但这是
I'm passionate about and uh I wanted to
我热爱的事情，我
go down that route enjoying it very much
想走这条路，我非常享受它，
so it's a great outlet for me why did
所以它对我来说是一个很好的发泄渠道。
you choose boxing despite the risks yeah
你为什么明知风险却仍然选择拳击？嗯，
I would say that boxing probably chose
我会说可能是拳击选择了
me instead of uh me choosing boxing I uh
我，而不是我选择了拳击。
I did Taekwondo growing up so I was in
我从小就练跆拳道，练了
martial arts for8 years and then um when
八年武术。后来，
I was in medical school I unfortunately
我在医学院读书的时候，不幸的是，我
lost my mom to cancer and that was a a
妈妈因癌症去世了。这件事
really strong wakeup call for me being
对我来说是一个沉重的打击。身处
in the medical field knowing what it's
医疗行业，我深知那种
like to be in the room to ask the
在病房里请求
doctors to stop doing chest compressions
医生停止对母亲进行胸外按压的痛苦。
on your mom I mean that is not something
我真心不
that I wish on anyone that's that's the
希望任何人经历这种事，这是
worst thing you can experience
你能经历的最糟糕的事情。
especially when my father was there also
尤其是我父亲也在场，他也是
a doctor who was saying no keep going
一名医生，他却说“不，继续按压”，
but I knew was futile I knew we were
但我知道这样做是徒劳的，我知道我们只会
causing more harm and in going through
造成更大的伤害。在
that journey I got into a very unhealthy
那段日子里，我的精神状态非常糟糕，
except to go to class I came home I was
除了去上课，我哪儿也不去。回家后，我把自己
socially isolated and after a period of
封闭起来，与世隔绝。这种情况持续了
3 four months where that was going on I
三四个月后，我
said I need to get out of this I need to
意识到我必须摆脱这种状态，我必须
take the my own advice that I give to
听从自己给
people and take the advice that you need
别人的建议，听从“你需要积极
to have action before you get motivation
行动”的建议。 在你获得动力之前，
and the action that I took was to go
我采取的行动是去
on guilt City do you remember that app
Guilt City（你还记得这个应用吗？
it's like a group ones app where you can
它有点像Group Ones，你可以在上面
get a coupon to a a class and I got a
获得课程优惠券。我获得了
coupon for a boxing class and I went and
一张拳击课的优惠券，然后我就去上了
did this boxing session and then I ended
这节课。之后我一练就是
up boxing for 10 years after that
十年，在那
then a couple years ago I ended up
之后我爱上了这项运动。几年前，我竟然在
fighting on Showtime pay-per-view in
Showtime的付费电视上比赛，
front of an audience of 15,000 people
面对15000名观众，
wow and uh it's it's been a unique
哇！这真是一段独特的
Journey so while it's easier to vilify
旅程。虽然人们很容易妖魔化
boxing and say that it's problematic for
拳击，说它对
some people if the trade-off is right it
某些人来说有问题，但如果权衡利弊，它
might be something that uh they could
或许是他们可以
participate in and it could be very
参与的，而且对
them losing your
他们的健康非常有益。失去
mother for anybody I think is just
母亲对任何人来说都是
unimaginably painful but in the
难以想象的痛苦，但就
circumstances that you lost your mother
你失去母亲的情况而言，据
where from what I understood she was
我了解，她
given the all clear at one point with
一度被告知已经痊愈。她患的是一种
of cancer called
叫做慢性淋巴细胞白血病（CLL）的特殊癌症，
CLL and this is usually a cancer of old
这通常是一种癌症。 很多时候，老年人被
age where you get diagnosed with it and
诊断出患有慢性淋巴细胞白血病（CLL），
you end
最终却
up dying of something else other than
死于其他疾病，而不是
that cancer but she had a unique more
癌症本身。但她患的是一种独特的、更具
aggressive form of CLL where they needed
侵袭性的CLL，需要加大
to really ramp up treatment and her
治疗力度。
treatment took a toll on her body
治疗对她的身体造成了很大的负担，
treatment she did not feel the same but
治疗后她的容貌和感觉都和以前不一样了。但这一切都是为了
it was all in the hopes of curing this
治愈
cancer and I remember very vividly I was
癌症。我清楚地记得，有一天
I was going to Memorial Sloan ketering
我去纪念斯隆-凯特琳癌症
hospital to pick her up one day and she
中心接她，她
actually fell waiting for me at the
在
waiting area so the doctor came down and
候诊区等我的时候摔倒了。医生下来和
talked to me and said maybe we should
我谈话，说也许应该让
keep her observation for a day or so um
她留院观察一天左右。他说，
but overall she's doing great she's just
总的来说她情况很好，只是
very weak from the treatment and he
治疗后身体很虚弱。医生当时
shook my hand in that moment and said
握着我的手说，
she's cured there's no more cancer in
她已经痊愈了，
her body now we just got to get her to
她体内已经没有癌细胞了。现在我们只需要让她
recover from all these treatments and
从这些治疗中恢复过来。这
that's the greatest news anyone can hear
是任何人都能听到的最好的消息，
your hopes 10 out of
希望值爆表。
10 and just a few short days
然而仅仅几天
later her weakness got so severe that
后，她的虚弱程度就急剧恶化，
blood causing gram negative sepsis
血液中感染了一种非常特殊的细菌，叫做革兰氏阴性菌。 革兰氏阴性菌败血症
spread throughout her body she required
扩散到她全身，她需要
the use of Presser medication to
服用升压药来人为
artificially raise her blood pressure to
地提高血压，以
prevent her organs from dying and it
防止器官衰竭，但药物无效，
didn't work and unfortunately she lost
她不幸去世。最
her life and one of the hardest moments
痛苦的时刻之一就是
there was watching my father go through
看着我的父亲经历这一切。他
this who with my mom sacrificed their
和我的母亲为了把
lives to bring us to the United States
我们这些移民带到美国，牺牲了自己的生命。
as immigrants gave up their lives he
他
went to medical school for a second time
第二次进入医学院学习，而我的母亲
having a PhD in Russia to learn English
在俄罗斯获得博士学位后，又去大学学习英语，以便将来能在
in the states
美国教学生数学。
it it was um it was painful to watch my
看着
dad go through it so I think for the
父亲经历这一切，真的非常痛苦。我想，在
first few
最初的
months my focus was more on him than it
几个月里，我的注意力更多地放在他身上，而不是我
myself did that experience change your
自己身上。那段经历是否以任何方式改变了你
perspective of medicine and the medical
对医学和医疗
industry in any way because in that
行业的看法？因为在那
moment a doctor a doctor turned to you
一刻，一位医生转向你，
and said your mother is cured and it
告诉你你的母亲已经痊愈了。
wasn't the it sounds like it wasn't the
听起来，造成
cancer itself that did the harm it was
伤害的不是癌症本身，而是
the treatment for the cancer that did
癌症治疗。
I never was mad at the doctor for saying
我从未因为医生这么说而生气，在那种
situation like that where you thought
情况下，你很容易会觉得自己已经康复了。
you were good but then it wasn't it
但后来并非如此。它
taught me a lesson about how life can be
教会了我一个道理：生活有时很
cruel and take things away from you very
残酷，
quickly after just receiving good news I
刚收到好消息就可能迅速夺走一切。我
remember sharing a a meme on my
记得当时我在Instagram上分享了一个表情包，上面写着“
Instagram that it had like you colon I'm
你……我
actually happy right now and then life
现在真的很开心”，然后是“生活……等等”，
second and that's kind of kind of how
这大概就是
life
生活的写照。
is so it taught me to be able to bounce
它教会了我如何
back from adversity and realize that you
从逆境中恢复过来，并意识到你
have to put one foot in front of the
必须一步一步地走下去，
other while still being able to feel
同时也要保持感受的能力。
because repressing emotions in the short
因为短期内压抑情绪
term is a valuable tool you know if
是一种有效的应对策略。你知道，如果
you're unable to function in terms of
你在
high stress in the moment you could lose
压力巨大的情况下无法正常生活，你可能会失去
your life you could make a really bad
生命，可能会做出非常糟糕的
decision you could harm others
决定，可能会伤害他人，甚至
you might not be able to successfully
可能无法
hold down a job but if you do that for a
保住工作。但如果你
really long period of time even that as
长期这样做，即使是这种短期
a aute coping strategy can become toxic
应对策略也会变得有害。
and I was getting into that point where
我当时的情况就是这样，
it was becoming chronic and I was
它已经变成了慢性病，我
blocking my feelings of not mourning my
压抑着自己的情绪，不愿去哀悼我的
mom not having the proper process and
母亲，没有经历应有的哀悼过程。
for everyone that process will be
每个人的哀悼过程都不
different you moved in with your father
一样。之后你搬去和你父亲一起住了。是的，
after that yep if I was a if I was a fly
如果我是一只苍蝇 在那间
on the wall in that in that household at
房子的墙上，当时你会
observed
看到
two gentlemen trying to raise a dog very
两个男人笨手笨脚地养着一条狗，
poorly that's probably not what you
这可能不是你
expected but I um in trying to always
想看到的。但我总是想方设法地想办法
find some kind of way to help um I
帮忙，我
thought by helping my dad redirect his
想通过帮助我父亲转移他的
feelings towards something else um I got
注意力，于是我给
a Siberian Husky for him in that moment
他买了一只西伯利亚哈士奇。
which we always wanted a dog even my mom
我们一直都想要养狗，连我妈妈也
wanted the dog and uh he took some time
想要。
to travel to more in my mother's
在我母亲
passing and while he was doing that I
去世后，他去外地待了一段时间，在他外出期间，我稍微照顾了一下那条狗，养了
raised a dog a little bit for a few
几个
weeks got her at least potty trained and
星期，至少教会了它定点大小便。
then when he came home she was there he
然后他回家的时候，狗就在那里。他像个
was typical Soviet father yelling at me
典型的苏联父亲一样对我大吼大叫，
and telling me why this is a bad idea
告诉我这是个糟糕的主意，还
crying which I never saw in my father
哭了。我以前从未见过我父亲这样，
before obviously until the loss of my
直到我母亲去世。
um then he started being happy
后来他开始高兴起来，
he started saying what should we call
开始问我们该给
her his Focus shifted his Focus shifted
它取什么名字。他的注意力转移到了带
to going for walks with her which
它散步上，这
allowed him to think about my mom to not
让他可以想起我母亲，而不是像
be locked into the house as so many
很多
people are when they're going through a
人在经历
rough time so while I think it was
艰难时期那样把自己封闭在家里。所以，虽然我觉得我们当时的情况很
chaotic of us trying to raise this puppy
混乱，但我们 一起养这只小狗让
together it gave us something to bond
我们
around in a moment of tough times there
在艰难时刻有了共同的依靠。
will be a lot of people listening right
现在可能有很多听众正经历着失去亲人的
grief or the throws of Their Own sadness
悲痛，或者
or depression for whatever reason right
因为其他原因陷入悲伤或抑郁之中，对吧？
and it's um when you're in the midst of
当你身处
the storm when it's it's hard to see any
风暴中心，看不到任何
way out and you said something super
出路的时候，你刚才说的很
interesting which is you said you
有意思，你说你
realize that like action comes before
意识到行动先于动机。是的，
motivation yep if I if I'm someone
如果我
that's in that situation right now and
现在正处于那种境地，
I'm listening what would you say to that
我会对正在听你讲话的
person put on your
人说什么呢？穿上你的
shoes they'll you'll go somewhere
鞋子，去某个地方走走，去哪儿都
doesn't matter where you'll go Chim not
无所谓。去
Jim walk dog park you can go to a dog
遛狗公园，即使不带狗也可以去。
dog it's
这是一种疗愈，
therapy the biggest therapy that I think
我认为是
I've ever had and I've gone through
我经历过的最有效的疗愈方式。我以前也接受过
traditional therapy was going to a dog
传统的心理治疗，但
park with my dog after my mom passed
妈妈去世后，我带着我的狗去遛狗公园就是最好的疗愈方式。
away it's such a weird thing but animal
这听起来很奇怪，但动物
therapy is
疗法是
real and you know who actually gave me
真实存在的。你知道是谁给我
that advice speaking of Dragons Den um
这个建议的吗？说到《龙穴》节目，是
Barbara corkran oh really she said that
芭芭拉·科克伦。哦，真的吗？ 她说，
the way that she gets herself to
她之所以能让自己
exercise cuz she doesn't like to she
锻炼，是因为她不喜欢锻炼，她讨厌锻炼，而且
hates it she's very vocal about it but
她对此毫不掩饰。但
she says next to her bed are her shoes
她说，她的
her athletic shoes that if she puts them
运动鞋就放在床边，如果穿上它们，
on she's like all right well since I
她就会想，好吧，既然穿上了，
have them on I may as well go exercise
不如就去锻炼一下。
and that one little step creates that
这小小的一步就能打造出那种
Cascade look will it work for everybody
瀑布般的效果。这种方法对每个人都有效吗？
is this the Miracle Solution no but it's
这是灵丹妙药吗？当然不是。但这确实只是
one step and even if you just do that
一步。即使你只做了这
one step and nothing else the next time
一步，下次
it'll be easier to put on the shoes and
穿鞋也会更容易，
maybe try for the second
也许可以尝试穿第二
one putting on the shoes is hot as well
双。
showering is hard grooming is
穿鞋的时候也很热，洗澡很热，梳洗也很热，
hard the basics of all Basics is
所有最基本的事情都
hard that's why when I hear advice like
很难。这就是为什么当我听到“心情低落的时候
go make some friends online when you're
去网上交些朋友”之类的建议时，我会觉得这
advice that's not easy so the putting on
建议太难了，一点也不容易。所以，
the shoes thing is simple in the sense
穿鞋这件事之所以简单，是因为它
of doesn't require others to be around
不需要别人在
you to judge you doesn't have any steps
你身边评判你，也不需要之后再做任何步骤，
after that just to put on the the shoes
只需要穿上鞋就行了。
and if you're at that point seeking help
如果你到了那种地步，那就应该寻求
from a medical professional is of utmost
医疗专业人士的帮助。 这
importance because we've put this stigma
至关重要，因为我们对
where if you go for mental health
心理健康存在一种偏见，认为寻求心理健康
treatment you're somehow weak but if you
治疗就意味着软弱，但接受
go for treatment for a broken bone
骨折治疗却不被视为
you're not weak that stigma doesn't
软弱，这种偏见并不
exist for it and that's strange because
存在。这很奇怪，因为
both things can have problems arise with
两者都可能出现问题，
it especially from a mental health
尤其是在心理健康
standpoint especially with the society
方面，尤其是在
we find ourselves in currently Society
我们目前所处的社会环境中。这个社会对
humans how would you describe the
人类而言是前所未有的不自然。你会如何描述
journey you've been on with your own
你自己的
mental
心理
health I don't know how I would describe
健康历程？我不知道该如何描述这段
the journey I I would say just like most
历程。我会说，就像大多数
people it's had ups and
人一样，我的心理健康之路也经历过
downs I would say the the thing that's
起伏。
really thrown me for a loop is the
真正让我感到困惑的是
social media world of it all because of
社交媒体的世界，因为它太不
how unnatural that that is but I feel
自然了。但我感觉
like a lot of people are working through
很多人即使
that without even having a social media
没有社交媒体
platform because at the end of the day
平台也在努力克服这些问题，因为归根结底，
these days everyone's a content
如今每个人都是内容
creator right like when you make a video
创作者，对吧？当你制作一个视频
and it gets millions of views you kind
并获得数百万的点击量时，你大概
of know what to expect being a content
知道会发生什么。作为内容创
creator you have experience but Johnny
作者，你有经验，但像Johnny、
Rebecca someone else putting out a video
Rebecca这样的人发布内容……
on their social media at 16 years old
他们16岁时在社交媒体上发布了一个视频，点击量竟然
that too can get a million views and
达到了百万，但
they're not ready for what comes with a
他们并没有准备好面对
million views in fact so many people
百万点击量带来的压力。事实上，很多人，
even in the medical community reach out
甚至包括医疗界人士，都会联系他们，
and say how do I go viral I'm like do
问我如何才能爆红。我当时就想，你们真的想爆红吗？
viral that's thrown your your mental
这确实让我精神状态
heal through a bit of a loop yeah I was
有点崩溃。是的，我当时非常
obsessed with it checking it all the
着迷，总是查看点击量。但我着迷的
the reason most people think I was
原因和大多数人认为的不一样，我
obsessed with it from a place of growth
着迷是出于成长的考量。我想，
I was like even if they're 99% BS
即使这些评论99%都是胡说八道，但其中也包含
there's some kind of truth there's a
一些
kernel of Truth there that I could take
真理，一些我可以
away and make myself better and you know
借鉴并让自己变得更好的东西。你知道，这其中确实
there is truth to that I did learn a lot
有道理。我的确学到了很多
of things I did prevent some mistakes
东西，避免了一些错误，也通过
listening to negative feedback and
倾听负面反馈和
criticism but I've had to in working
批评改进了我的内容。但我和
with my therapist carve out moments
我的治疗师一起努力，找出一些
where I'm not in a place where that's
我
acceptable for me right now where you
目前无法接受这些评论和批评的时刻。你
just have to say this I'm not in a
必须承认，我现在的
healthy mindset to look what was the
心态并不健康，无法去审视这些评论和批评。
of the impact it was having on
它对你造成的影响的症状是
you um tremendous
极度
anxiety where you're just worried at all
焦虑，你会时刻担忧，
times and you're almost addicted to
几乎上瘾地
checking it because you want to be ahead
查看信息，因为你想领先一步，
of it you want to be safe you want to be
想确保安全，想提前想好
response and when you get to that point
应对措施。当你达到那种状态时，你
you're never letting your mind rest
的大脑就无法休息，
you're always in fight or flight and
总是处于战斗或逃跑的应激状态。而
when you're in fight or flight you're
当你处于这种状态时，你就
not resting you're not repairing you're
无法休息，无法修复，也
not getting good quality sleep even so I
无法获得高质量的睡眠。我
know how important that is I talk about
知道睡眠的重要性，我一直在谈论
it all the time but as I said you know
它，但正如我所说，
we're all not perfect doctors are
我们都不是完美的人。医生在自身健康方面
probably the biggest Hypocrites when it
可能是最大的伪君子。
comes to their own health I guarantee
我敢保证，
you some of the people that have come on
一些来我
your podcast that talk about sleep or
播客谈论睡眠或
talk about
谈论
this they struggle with sleep they don't
这些的人，他们自己也睡眠不足，他们并没有
do those things just like how some
做到我所说的那些。就像
advice that I give I don't follow to the
我给出的一些建议，我也不会完全遵循。
tea my job is just to present the
我的工作只是呈现
evidence so I know certain things that I
证据，所以我知道有些事情我
should be doing better but just because
应该做得更好，但这
I know doesn't mean that I'm going to be
并不意味着我会一直
100% following it all the time this is
百分之百地遵循它。 这很
interesting thing that I I was just
有意思，我刚才就在
thinking about as you're saying that
想，就像你说的，从
that um at like a philosophical level I
哲学层面来说，我
think we're all kind of just passing our
觉得我们都在不知不觉中把
anxiety on to someone else like it's
焦虑传递给别人，就像
like energy cannot be destroyed and must
能量无法被摧毁，只能
be transferred I I noticed this because
转移一样。我注意到这一点是因为
on my podcast I have multiple guests
我的播客里有很多嘉宾，他们
that often disagree with each other and
经常意见不合。
if I was to do a map of how those people
如果我画一张图来展示这些人的
are feeling they're all suffering well
感受，他们都会感到痛苦，
that's just Humanity as a whole they're
其实整个人类都在受苦，他们真的都在
all like really suffering and sometimes
受苦。有时候，
those people are suffering because of
这些人受苦是因为
someone else who suffered and then
别人受苦，然后又
because of someone else's it's almost
因为别人受苦，这就形成了一个
like this this chain of suffering
痛苦的链条，
because of misunderstanding a variety of
因为误解，因为
different reasons but I think as you say
各种各样的原因。但我觉得就像你说的，
Humanity as a whole the person that's
整个人类都在受苦。
leaving those messages or you know
那些给你留言或者
attacking you is probably also suffering
攻击你的人，可能也在
in their own way of course it's a real
以他们自己的方式受苦。当然，这很
shame but I can't see any way out it's
遗憾，但我看不到任何出路。
it's a like the circle of anxiety is an
这就像一个焦虑的循环，当然，用“焦虑的循环”
artistic way to put it for sure um but I
来形容可能有点艺术化，但我
think there's there's some truth to it
认为其中确实包含一些真理。
you know uh even from trauma the odds
创伤，
are that if you've experienced a
如果你经历过
traumatic childhood that you will also
创伤性的童年，那么你给
potentially cause trauma to others goes
他人造成创伤的可能性也会
up that risk does go up and that's also
增加。这种风险确实会增加，这其实也是
pretty Common Sense even if you're not
常识。即使不
looking at the medical research you
看医学研究，你也
could just say that if you've been hurt
可以说，如果你曾经受过伤害，
ozar you can hurt people what do they
你也可能伤害别人。人们常说，
say hurt people hurt people too right um
伤害过的人也会伤害别人，对吧？嗯，
I think that that's like uh that Common
我认为这是一种
Sense logic that does get it right
常识性的逻辑，确实没错。
what's the um did your therapist give
你的治疗师有没有给
you any advice that's proven to be
你什么
useful well the advice that you put
有用的建议？你提到的建议非常
perfectly in in place of logging off not
完美，比如在一天中的某些时间不要
looking at certain things at certain
查看某些内容。
times of the day like literally I had to
我真的必须在
times of the day because otherwise what
一天中的某些时间完全关掉手机，否则我
happens is I would get into the cycle of
就会陷入这样的循环：
okay I just finished in the hospital I
刚从医院出来，
just filmed my video for the day now
刚拍完今天的视频，现在
it's sleep time and just before going
该睡觉了，就在
into bed let's check my phone one last
上床睡觉之前，我还要最后查看一下手机，
time and search the social media sites
浏览一下社交媒体，看看
what people are saying and it's like
人们在说什么。
why that's ultim Ely what I think
为什么会这样？我觉得
probably got me healthier like not
真正让我更健康的，就是不要
looking at it was very good in moments
去看那些东西。 在绝望的时刻，它确实非常有用，
of Despair because during those moments
因为在那些时刻
I was just so fragile and it would not
我非常脆弱，根本不适合浏览社交媒体。
be a good time to look but really where
但它真正让
it got me is what got me is don't look
我明白的是，
unless there's something valuable you're
除非你能从中获得有价值的东西，否则不要去看。
getting from looking at it so now if I'm
所以现在，如果我状态
in a healthy place and I feel like I'm
良好，感觉自己在浏览社交媒体，
looking and I'm doing some kind of
并且是在做一些
preventive task I'm learning from it I'm
预防性的事情，比如从中学习，我就会想：
like okay I'm looking at it but I'm
好吧，我是在看，但我是带着
looking at it with some kind of
某种
intention and that's actually true for
目的去看的。事实上，这适用于
all of social media I think um he was on
所有社交媒体。我想，
your show as well Dr Robert waldinger
罗伯特·瓦尔丁格博士也上过你的节目。他
running study at Harvard of Happiness
在哈佛大学主持了规模最大、持续时间最长的幸福研究，他
talked about the different usages of
谈到了社交媒体的不同用途。
social media how if you use social media
如果你被动地使用社交媒体，
passively and you just look and consume
只是浏览和消费，
it can be rather disheartening and make
这可能会相当令人沮丧，让
you unhappy but if you use it to form a
你不快乐；但如果你用它来建立一个
community to learn from it to better
社群，从中学习，提升
yourself suddenly the social media may
自己，那么社交媒体对
not have as bad of a health impact and
健康的影响可能就不会那么糟糕，反而会对
can actually have a positive mental
心理
health impact so if I'm looking at the
健康产生积极的影响。所以，如果我浏览的是
negative comments I'd have to do that
负面评论， 我得好好
check-in with myself of am I doing this
反思一下，我做这些事是
because I'm actually benefiting from it
真的从中受益，
or is it destructive in
还是
nature have you ever wondered if there's
本质上有害？你有没有想过，是不是
something about you that makes
你身上有什么特质让
you more likely to look at that stuff or
你更容易关注或
to care about that stuff I've often
关心这些东西？我经常思考这个问题。是的，我觉得我有。
pretty natural thing I think most people
我觉得这很自然，大多数人都会关注这些。
look um I think for me
对我来说，我
I do on social media because this was
在社交媒体上的工作很有价值，因为这从来都不是为了
never meant to be a financial Venture
赚钱，也不是什么必须
had to make myself successful this was
让自己成功的宏大理念。这
solely because of my frustration as a
完全是因为我作为一名
practicing doctor which the first
执业医生感到沮丧。我刚开始玩社交媒体时，
question ever anyone ever asked me when
别人问我的第一个问题就是：
you're doing so well you must want to
你现在这么成功，是不是想
quit medicine right like you're probably
放弃行医了？你是不是觉得你
out earning it yeah but that's not why I
赚的钱比当医生还多？是啊，但这并不是我当
do medicine I work at a community health
医生的原因。我在社区卫生中心工作。大多数在
on social media either leave medicine or
社交媒体上做得好的医生要么会放弃行医，要么会
maybe do concierge practice or you know
去做私人医生，或者给
celebrity practice or something I work
名人看病什么的。我
at a community health center where 50%
在社区卫生中心工作。 那里有50%
of people don't have
的人没有
insurance so that's been my goal and
保险，所以这就是我的目标，而
social media is just a tool to help me
社交媒体只是帮助我
with that goal and when I see negative
实现这个目标的工具。当我看到负面
comments I view it as a threat to that
评论时，我会把它视为对这个
goal have you ever considered quitting
目标的威胁。你有没有认真考虑过退出
social
社交
media seriously I pondered what life
媒体？我认真思考过如果退出社交媒体生活
would be like um but I just viewed it as
会是什么样子，嗯，但我感觉它对各方面都是
a negative all around not just for me I
负面的，不仅仅是对我个人而言。我认为
just VI view as social media such an
社交媒体是一个
opportunity to help people it's like me
帮助他人的机会，就像我
saying quitting medicine I don't want to
说要放弃医学一样。我不想
quit medicine I I want to be there for
放弃医学，我想帮助
people I want to be valuable and useful
别人，我想成为有价值、有用的人。
I in fact I think about myself as like a
事实上，我认为自己是一个
more practical useful person and every
比较务实、有用的人，
strength that everyone has can also be
每个人的优点也可能成为
their weakness so sometimes I'm too
缺点。所以有时候我太务实了，
practical and that impacts you as a
这会影响到你，无论是作为
friend as a partner as a family member
朋友、伴侣还是家人。
so sometimes being too practical is
所以有时候太务实是有
problematic but because of my practical
问题的，但正因为我的务实
nature I want to be useful to my
性格，我才想对我的
patients so let's continue with this um
病人有用。那么我们继续这个话题，关于
this health related stuff supplements
健康相关的内容，比如补充剂
and vitamins I wanted to get your take
和维生素。我想听听你的
on that there's a lot of you've
看法，你们很多人都
mentioned supplements and a few times in
提到了补充剂，在
this
这次
conversation is that part of the gray
谈话中也提到了好几次。补充剂是……的一部分吗？ 灰色
area is that snake oil what's your POV
地带就是那些所谓的“灵丹妙药”。你
on
对
supplements I want to say like one
保健品有什么看法？我想用
sentence that is all-encompassing and
一句话概括
answers all those questions but it's
所有问题，但这
really hard because there's just so much
真的很难，因为这里面有很多
Nuance with it um
细微差别。嗯，
vitamins we can't live without them we
维生素，我们离不开它们，我们
need them supplements supplemental
需要它们，但补充剂，
vitamins are not necessary the huge
维生素补充剂在绝大多数情况下并非必需品，
majority of the time and are often sold
而且它们往往是
by people who are praying on
由那些利用
Securities promising
证券市场牟利、承诺
shortcuts and honestly people trying to
捷径、甚至想发财的人兜售的。
supplements unless you have a very
除非你有非常
specific reason for needing to take them
具体的理由需要服用，否则几乎所有保健品都缺乏证据支持。
missing and what I've learned at through
我作为一名
my 10 years of being a physician
医生十年的经验，
and the hundreds of years of practice of
以及数百年的
medicine unless we're certain of some
医学实践经验告诉我，除非我们确信某些
benefit introducing new things
益处，否则引入新产品、
distracting people from things that work
分散人们对有效疗法的注意力
is not a good solution is the harm of
并不是一个好办法。
supplements that they don't actually
保健品的危害在于它们实际上无效。
work again with supplements is a broad
再次强调，“保健品”是一个宽泛的
word so probably have to be is it the
词，所以可能需要进一步探讨：
harm that they don't work or is are you
危害在于它们无效，还是
saying that we should be getting all of
说我们应该
the things that we're supplementing from
从
our natural diet anyway or are you
天然饮食中获取所有需要补充的营养？或者你的
saying both yes
意思是两者都是？
again unless you have a specific medical
除非你有特定的
condition from foods
疾病，否则不要从食物中摄取所有营养。
to they will make you skip out on doing
它们会让你放弃一些对
things that are healthy for you because
你健康有益的事情，因为
you think you can take a shortcut three
你认为可以走捷径。
you're spending your limited health care
你会把有限的医疗
budget that many people have a very
预算（很多人的
limited health care Budget on things
医疗预算本来就非常有限）花在
that are very expensive making a lot of
非常昂贵的、
promises and the thing that I'm most
承诺很多的东西上。我最
worried about is when we enter the space
担心的是，当
of people saying you need supplements
人们开始说你需要补充剂
and not true Medical Treatments for
而不是真正的医疗方法来治疗困扰或
affect them if I'm someone that maybe
影响他们的疾病时。如果我是一个饮食非常单一的人（
I'm not talking about myself here but if
我这里不是在说我自己），
choices whatever would you recommend
你会建议他
that individual to take a multivitamin
服用复合维生素
supplement I probably
补充剂吗？我可能
wouldn't but if they did I wouldn't
不会，但如果他服用了，我也不会
discourage them do they work that's what
阻止他。它们真的有效吗？这就是
I'm trying to figure out oh and then the
我想弄清楚的。哦，还有一点
other point that I didn't mention is
我没提到，
that there's harm like you said
就像你说的，
everything has trade-offs there's no
任何事物都有利弊，没有绝对
such thing as no side effects so
没有副作用的东西。
supplements have side effects they have
补充剂也有副作用，它们会
interactions with medications they can
与药物相互作用，它们可能会
create health conditions uh the term
引发健康问题。
antioxidants antioxidants are generally
抗氧化剂这个词，通常来说，抗氧化剂是
healthy uh you know B vitamins are
有益健康的。你知道，B族维生素
traditionally labeled as healthy you
传统上被认为是健康的。但是，
have too many of them we notice that
我们注意到，摄入过多的B族维生素会导致
they become pro-inflammatory but no one
炎症，但没人
talks about that because you can't
谈论这一点，因为这不利于产品的
really sell that so what instead gets
销售。所以人们
talked about is the promise of what they
谈论的更多是它们可能带来的益处。然而，
from taking supplements especially in
服用补充剂也会带来危害，尤其是在
our world where you know consumer labs
我们这个时代，消费者实验室
and Consumer Reports goes and pulls
和消费者报告等机构会把一些
supplements off the shelves to find out
补充剂从货架上取下来，发现
that they don't have the ingredients
它们并不包含标签
that are listed in them because they're
上列出的成分。因为它们
not regulated by the Food and Drug
不受美国食品药品监督
Administration they have some
管理局（FDA）的监管，有些
ingredients at 5 to 10x what's on the
成分的含量是标签上标明的5到10倍，
label like vitamin A which is a fat
比如维生素A，这是一种
soluble vitamin and can actually be
脂溶性维生素，实际上可能
really harmful so they're not regulated
非常有害。所以，由于不受监管，
they can cause potential harm their
它们可能造成潜在的危害。
benefit unless very clearly indicated is
除非有非常明确的说明，否则它们的益处只是
in the air and not proven why recommend
空谈，没有得到证实。为什么要推荐
them why sell
它们？为什么要销售
them and I say this as someone who can
它们？我作为一个可以从中获利的人，这么说是因为
fortune I mean you said to yourself 12
你……
subscribers you know I take a little
你知道，我有1200万订阅者，我经常拍个
boxing selfie fit and say the reason I'm
拳击自拍，然后说我身材
this fit is because I take whatever
这么好是因为我把
thing I bottled up in my house put into
家里各种东西都装进
those pills whatever powder I want no
药丸里，想加什么粉末就加什么粉末，没
one checks it and I could sell it and
人检查，我可以卖掉它，
become a multi-millionaire is that sure
成为千万富翁。真的
that no one checks it no one checks it
没人检查吗？没人检查吗？
these supplements
这些补品，真的没人检查吗？
no like right now we could bottle up on
现在我们就可以把
the table our Miracle formula we can
我们的“神奇配方”装瓶放在桌子上，
call it a miracle formula yeah as long
就叫它“神奇配方”了。
as we don't make a claim that it treats
只要我们不声称它能治疗
requires the treatment of a medical
需要医生治疗的特定疾病就行。
doctor okay and I just put buzzwords on
好吧，我就用一些流行词，比如，与其说它能缓解
saying this helps your depression I just
抑郁，不如说它能增强
say depression immunity support just
免疫力，就是一些流行
buzzwords feel good feel good happy
词，比如“感觉良好”、“感觉良好”、“快乐”、“自然”、“
happy natural simple from the earth we
简单”、“来自大自然”。我们
could sell it how much we don't have to
可以卖掉它，我们不需要任何人的批准，我们不需要任何
anything cleared by anybody how much you
人的批准。你
think we'd
觉得我们能
make too much money and that's why it's
赚多少钱？这就是为什么，
like man I understand why people do it
我理解人们为什么这么做，
and there is the notion that they could
而且他们觉得这些产品
potentially work there's always like a
可能有效。总是有这种想法。
little bit of evidence coming out
一些证据正在浮出水面，
that're just going to cut break for
这可能会给“
miracle M which is
奇迹M”（Miracle M）带来冲击，它确实
on it's so tempting I get it and I get
很诱人，我理解这一点。我也明白，
there's also I don't want to label
我不想
everyone with a broad brush and say
一概而论，说所有人
they're evil and just trying to make
都是邪恶的，只是想
money some people do believe that they
赚钱。有些人确实相信这些产品有效，
work they they want the belief that this
他们想要相信这些产品能拯救
is what alss us as a
我们整个
society and I wish that was true I wish
社会，我希望这是真的，我希望
it was as simple as giving people some
事情真的像服用一些
supplements or that eating eight almonds
补充剂那么简单，或者每天吃八颗杏仁就能
a day will extend your life by 10 years
延寿十年。
I wish that was the case um the subject
我希望情况真是如此。嗯，
around gut microbiome is something that
关于肠道微生物群的话题，
I've talked about a lot on this podcast
我在这个播客里谈了很多，
because I've just had a lot of experts
因为很多专家都跟
talking to me about subject and
我讨论过这个话题，而
existed three years ago I didn't realize
三年前我甚至都不知道它的存在，我根本没意识到
there was loads of bugs in my belly
我的肚子里有很多微生物。
um there are prebiotics probiotics all
嗯，现在市面上出现了益生元、益生菌等等，所有这些都是
of these things coming out now for to
为了
enhance the what do they call it it's
增强……他们称之为……？
not gut Flora is it microbiota
不是肠道菌群，而是微生物群，它
encompasses all of it is there truth
包含了所有这些。
that prebiotics and probiotics are
益生元真的有效吗？ 益生菌确实
useful for well there's truth in the
有用，这没错，
fact that we have all of these living
我们体内确实存在各种各样的
organisms inside of us there's a very
微生物，
interconnectedness between how we feel
我们的
disease conditions and and what species
健康状况与
of those bugs exists in us the counts by
这些微生物的种类和数量之间存在着非常紧密的联系。
generally eat specific foods that are
经常食用富含特定微生物食物的人
rich in them may have better health
可能比
don't but
不食用的人健康状况更好，但大多数情况下，人为
manipulating those bugs has not been
操控这些微生物并没有得到
proven or clear in the majority of ways
证实或明确的证据。比如，
that people promise they do like we know
我们知道
consuming fiber correlates With Better
摄入膳食纤维与更好的
Health less negative health
健康状况和更少的负面健康
outcomes do we know that taking a
结果相关，但我们知道服用
Prebiotic supplement does the same we
益生元补充剂也能达到同样的效果吗？我们并不清楚。
don't know do we know that having
我们知道，
destroyed if you have a health condition
如果患有某种疾病，肠道中的特定细菌就会被破坏，
we do know that but does that mean
但这并不意味着
reestablishing it by taking it in a pill
服用益生元就能
will fix that condition we don't know
治愈疾病。我们并不清楚。
that but people will make that jump and
但人们却会这样想，
say no big deal we're trying to help but
说这没什么大不了的，我们只是想帮助别人。但对
to me it's a big deal because we're
我来说，这很成问题，因为我们
promising something that we're uncertain
承诺了一些我们不确定的事情，甚至连
of without even some good evidence for
一些可靠的证据都没有。
probiotics can actually help with well
益生菌真正能帮助的疾病非常少。那么，有
what advice would you give someone that
什么建议呢？ 如果一位病人来
comes into your practice and you
就诊，你
identify that they have some kind of gut
发现他/她存在某种
related gut microbiome related issue is
肠道菌群相关的问题，你会
there anything that you would recommend
建议他/她做些什么来
that they do to improve that got micro
改善肠道菌群呢？我会建议他/她多吃对肠道
microbiome so foods that are rich in
菌群有益的食物，比如富含
fiber plants essentially um avoiding bad
纤维的植物性食物。同时，也要避免不良
habits poor quality sleep over drinking
习惯，比如睡眠不足、过度饮酒、
alcohol smoking all those things are
吸烟等等，这些都不健康。
makes Health advice so boring is that
健康建议之所以枯燥乏味，是因为
what I say in my office and it's not
我讲的都是奶奶辈的老生常谈，这些话现在依然适用。它们听起来
sexy and it puts people to sleep but
枯燥乏味，甚至会让人昏昏欲睡，但却
it's true that's what we know works we
是真理，是我们知道有效的方法。我们虽然
don't have a perfect answer as to why
无法完全解释其中的原因，但
and right now there's like tests on the
目前
market to check your microbiome to know
市面上有一些检测肠道菌群、了解
what food too preliminary to recommend
哪些食物有益的测试，但这些测试结果还不够成熟，
we don't know what to do with the
我们不知道该如何利用这些
information the promises that they make
信息。这些测试所做出的承诺，
don't hold up when we look at it long
从长远来看，并不值得推荐。
term genetic tests potential is there
基因检测虽然具有
for a lot of value most of them are very
很大的潜力，但大多数测试结果都还处于
preliminary unless you're working with a
初步阶段，除非你与
geneticist on a very specific condition
遗传学家合作研究某种非常具体的疾病。
so I think the hype often times speeds
所以我认为，目前对基因检测的炒作还不够充分。 很多时候，在证据不足的情况
up the selling of the products before
下就加速产品销售，这种做法
the evidence is there it outpaces the
超越了
evidence and in some instances medicine
证据的积累。在某些情况下，医学领域也存在这种情况，
does that too like traditional medicine
比如传统医学，
but it does that with some thought in
但这种做法是经过
mind for example if we create an
深思熟虑的。例如，如果我们发布
emergency use authorization or if we
紧急使用授权，或者
allow someone to have a treatment
允许某人
exemption for something that is not
对某种未经
proven for a disease that's already
证实的疗法进行治疗豁免，而这种疗法对某种致命疾病仍然有效，那么
lethal that they're going to lose their
他们
life anyway or if we don't act now we're
无论如何都会失去生命；或者如果我们现在不采取行动，就会立即
going to lose so many lives in the
失去很多生命。
moment then yeah there might be
那么，是的，在某些
instances where we can speed up the
情况下，我们或许可以加快某些
process of certain things we can uh
流程，我们可以
create some shortcuts because we're
走一些捷径，因为我们
taking that trade-off that's thought
权衡了利弊，这是经过深思熟虑的。
about but with a lot of these products
但是，很多这类产品来来去去，
they come and go and there's just so
而且围绕
much misinformation around them you know
它们存在着大量的错误信息。你知道，
does this in this space and hate to
在这个领域，有一位举足轻重的人物——我不想点名批评他，
single out but it's just been such a um
但他
a a voice in this community is Gary Brea
在这个领域的声音非常响亮——就是加里·布雷亚。
you know I I talked about him on my show
我在我的节目中谈到过他，
have you spoke to him no
你和他谈过吗？没有。他
and seems like a really good person
看起来是个很好的人，
seems very passionate about what he's
对他所谈论的事情充满热情。
about but the the promises that are
这些承诺
being made are not
未经
proven and the intention may be good and
证实，出发点可能是好的，但
good intentions can have bad outcomes
好心办坏事。
but if the information is not accurate
如果信息不准确，
No matter how passionate you are about
无论你对这个话题多么热情，从
the subject long term it's going to have
长远来看，都会产生
negative outcomes when you use the word
负面结果。你用“证实”这个词，是指目前
yet to validate the hypotheses or the
还没有进行过大量或可靠的研究来验证这些假设或
statements or you're not saying that
说法吗？还是说你并没有说它已经
it's been disproven it just hasn't been
被证伪，只是还没有被证实？是的，你
bring up the things that I say that are
说的这一点很好，我所说的那些不
inaccurate largely have not been
准确的说法大多还没有被
disproven because if I say the juice
证伪。比如，如果我说
inside this cup will help you live
这杯果汁能让你
forever would you say that's true or
长生不老，你会觉得这是真的吗？
not I Theory would be that that's not
理论上来说，这肯定不是
true right but can you disprove it no
真的，对吧？但是你能证伪它吗？不能，
you would have to run a study to
你需要做一项研究才能
disprove it yeah and that's how I
证伪它。是的，我
function as a doctor so I can't disprove
作为一名医生就是这样工作的，所以我不能证伪
what he's saying because then I would
他说的，因为那样我就得自己
have to run my own study but based on
做研究了。但是根据
what we do know based on remember how I
我们已知的信息，记住我一
said at the beginning when a new study
开始说的…… 当有新的研究
comes out I try and bring it to the
出来时，我会尝试把它和
we have it doesn't Vibe with what we
我们已有的既有信息进行比较。如果它与我们
know to be true if you want to go
已知的真理不符，如果你想违背
what we've established as science you
我们已经确立的科学公共卫生标准，你
better have a good reason for doing it
最好能给出充分的理由。
and if you do I'm all ears I'm excited
如果你有，我会洗耳恭听，我很期待
for that kind of stuff if you have some
这类事情。如果你有什么
breakthrough of why you disagree with
突破性发现，能解释你为什么不同意
the CDC with the wh with uh Harvard
疾控中心、世界卫生组织或哈佛
Health please tell me why you disagree
健康中心的观点，请告诉我你的理由。
but if you disagree because you said so
但如果你只是因为自己说了算就反对，那就麻烦了。
I'll give you the simplest of examples
我举个最简单的例子：
there's a very famous clip that I
我
reacted to on my podcast where Gary Brea
在我的播客里回应过一个很著名的视频片段，Gary Brea
says if you have headaches it's because
说如果你头痛，那是因为
you're low on pink Himalayan sea
你缺乏喜马拉雅粉红
salt how many reasons do you think
海盐。你觉得
people get
人们
headaches many reasons you're not even
头痛的原因有多少？很多。
you're not even a doctor right my
你甚至都不是医生，对吧？
brother has my brother has had chronic
我哥哥从小就患有慢性
headaches since he was since he was a
头痛。
kid just you got a concussion you have
你可能得过脑震荡，压力过大，
stress you have a hormone issue you have
激素失衡，甚至长了
a tumor there's so many you have
肿瘤，原因太多了。你还可能患有
migraines you have a neck cramp what the
偏头痛。 脖子抽筋了，
possibilities are endless right
可能性无穷无尽，对吧？
to have the confidence to say this is
要有自信说，这就是
what you're
你
missing everything else Almost Doesn't
错过的，其他一切几乎都不
Matter the confidence is the
重要。自信源于
misinformation like notice every time
错误信息，比如你注意到
you asked me a question today it was
今天你问我的每个问题，我的回答要么是“
either I don't know it depends Nuance
我不知道”，要么是“这要看情况”。
for who it's almost annoying because I
这几乎让人恼火，因为我永远
can never give a clear answer but that's
无法给出明确的答案，但这就是
what science is and that's actually why
科学，也正是
people have lost trust in science
人们失去对科学信任的原因，
because we're not as confident as Gary
因为我们不像加里·
Brea when he talks about salt for
布雷亚那样自信，他谈到用盐治疗
headaches sometimes you've been wrong
头痛时，有时你会犯错，对吧？
right of course sometimes you've I
有时你会……我
remember reading um something where you
记得读过你
said I admit that I I change I've
说过的话，我承认，
changed my mindset when presented with
当面对新信息时，我会改变我的想法，
new information and I've explained why I
我也解释过为什么。
doctors this is the part I think that
我认为，当我们想到医生时，
some people struggle with is if you look
有些人难以理解的是，如果你回顾过去
over the course of sort 10 20 30 40
10年、20年、30年、40
years some of the things we were told
年，我们当时被告知的一些
were healthy back then are no longer
健康的东西现在已经不再
healthy and new information about I'm
健康了，而且关于……的新信息……我
well aware that this is a scientific
很清楚这是一个科学
model but I'm I'm trying to the coun
模型，但我……我试图……试图
trying to present the counter argument
呈现…… 反驳的观点是：
put yourself in that shoe in that seat
设身处地地想一想，当
doctors say that they've been wrong and
医生承认自己犯错，甚至在一些关键问题上
they've changed their mind on really
改变了看法时，我们该如何判断谁值得信任？就拿
when we think about vaccine
疫苗
disinformation right a lot of the
虚假信息来说，
arguments you'll get from the right are
右翼人士经常会说：“
that you said this and now look what
你以前是这么说的，现在看看
happened so we'll never trust you again
发生了什么，所以我们再也不会相信你了。”
how do we navigate and know who to
我们该如何辨别真伪，该
believe even doctors when doctors will
相信谁？即使是医生，当他们承认
say information I gave you in the past
过去提供的信息已经过时时，
was actually no longer true you have to
我们也必须
take the hard route and do the work to
付出努力，去
find out why they said what they said
探究他们过去为什么这么说，
then and why they're changing their mind
以及现在为什么改变了看法。
now so I'll give you an example y
我举个例子，
actually maybe this isn't a doctor this
也许这并非出自医生之口，而是来自一些研究。
is um studies I remember having a guest
我记得
on my podcast that talked about I think
我的播客节目里有一位嘉宾谈到，
depression drugs in the early years
早期的抗抑郁药物曾引发过一场危机。
where they had because of the way that
由于
the tests had been done by the big
大型
pharmaceutical
制药
companies the CEO of the pharmaceutical
公司进行的试验方式，制药
company knew that the depression drug
公司的首席执行官明知抗抑郁药物
did not work and had all these side
无效且
effects but they pushed it through even
副作用很大，却仍然强行推行，
though the vast majority of the studies
尽管绝大多数研究都表明药物
had hadn't shown that the drug worked
无效。 他们没有证明这种药有效，就
they found one study that had they
找到了一项研究，然后强行推向
pushed it through got to Market loads of
市场，很多
kids used it and then I think a decade
孩子都用了。然后，大概十年
later I again I'm paraphrasing here I
后（我这里是转述，我在
link what I'm talking about below it was
下面附上链接），人们
discovered that the CEO of that company
发现那家公司的CEO明明知道这药
knew it it didn't work but there was a
没用，但因为有
study and research that got it to Market
研究，它才得以上市，
and people started using it I think
人们开始用。我记得
Johan hary who's been on my podcast
约翰·哈里之前上过我的播客，就是
before he was the zmek episode we
我们
released um he was one of the people as
发布的Zmek那一期。他
a young man that started taking that
年轻时就开始服用这种
depression drug only to find out that
抗抑郁药，结果
five six years seven eight years later
五六七年后发现根本
it didn't work and the CEO knew that it
没用，而CEO也知道这药
wasn't really working so that was the
根本没用。这就是人们对
that was trust in the medical system it
医疗体系、对
that was trust in research that was
科研、对
trust in big farmer much of the counter
大型制药公司信任度下降的问题。
movement we're seeing now is we think
现在我们看到的很多反抗运动都认为大型
big farmer is corrupt and we think
制药公司腐败，认为
they're meddling with doctors to get
他们干预医生，把
drugs into Market that maybe don't work
可能无效的药物推向市场。
there's a lot of drugs on the market
市面上有很多药，
yeah if science is so problematic and we
没错，如果科学真的这么有问题，我们就不
shouldn't trust for all those reasons
应该完全信任它。
why is it the one example that we're
为什么我们要如此
stretching to find of the mistake that
执着地寻找这一个案例，来证明某种药物的错误
was happened or the fraud that happened
或欺诈行为？
with this one drug we're talking about
我们谈论的是
something that happened decades ago it
几十年前发生的事情，
does happen fraud happens it happens in
欺诈确实存在，
healthcare it happens with policing it
医疗保健领域存在欺诈，警务领域存在欺诈，
happens politicians there is fraud but
政界也存在欺诈，欺诈无处不在。但仅仅因为
pointing to that one episode and saying
一个案例就断言
we should throw the whole field away is
我们应该推翻整个行业，这会让
going to cause a loss for us and there
我们蒙受损失。
are issues with Pharma there's huge
制药行业存在问题，而且问题非常严重。
issues with Pharma I frequently talk
我经常谈到，
about even from like the pricing
即使从
standpoint of Pharma how problematic
制药的定价角度来看，他们的定价也存在诸多问题。
they are we've seen the issues with the
我们已经看到了阿片类药物危机，这场危机
largely by
很大程度上是由
Pharma but we're calling them out the
制药公司造成的。但我们正在揭露他们的错误。
beauty of Western medicine of what we do
西方医学的优势在于，
here is that we are the best at calling
我们最擅长承认
ourselves out on our failures but
自身的错误。但
actually the more we call ourselves out
实际上，我们越是承认自己的
on our failures the more trust we've
错误，就越容易
lost and in fact when someone owes up to
失去信任。事实上，当一个人勇于承认
their failures and seeks to learn from
自己的错误，并努力从中吸取教训，
them and seeks to make
努力做出
change that's the person you want to
改变时，这才是我们应该
follow the person who is not confident
追随的人——一个不自信、愿意
who is open to be transparent who
坦诚相待、
explains why these things are happening
解释原因的人。 很多事情的进展都
without 100% confidence that's the
无法百分之百确定，
people that are giving you advice that's
给你建议的人也是如此。就像
true the same way that we said uh
我们
earlier that everything is all natural
之前说的，所有东西都是天然的
does not mean it's all
并不意味着它们都是
good everything for profit is not
好的，所有以盈利为目的的东西也不
necessarily evil my YouTube channel is
一定都是邪恶的。我的YouTube频道就是
for profit I make a very healthy living
为了盈利，我靠我做的事情过着非常健康的生活，但这
doing what I'm doing doesn't mean it's
并不意味着我做的事情是
evil so while it's easy to make
邪恶的。所以，虽然很容易
shortcuts and overgeneralize we have to
走捷径和过度概括，但我们必须
talk about specific instances and call
讨论具体事例，并如实判断好坏。裁判也会犯错，
make mistakes healthcare industry has
医疗行业也
made mistakes there's been vaccine
犯过错，
incidents in the past that have hurt
过去发生过疫苗事故伤害了
people we've learned from them we called
人们，我们从中吸取了教训，我们指出了错误，
it out we've studied it we are con there
我们进行了研究，我们一直在努力改进。
are doctors constantly
医生们一直在
studying where we need to do better this
研究我们需要改进的地方。这种改进一直在进行，
is ongoing at all times and the ironic
讽刺的
part is most people have no idea that
是，大多数人对此一无所知，
it's happening because we only find out
因为我们只有在自己
about it on issues we're passionate
热衷的问题上才会注意到这些。
about I recently did a video or I was on
我最近做了一个视频，或者参加了
a podcast where I was asked about birth
一个播客节目，有人问到
control I gave a very simple answer it
避孕，我给出了一个非常简单的回答，
non motivated in any way it was just
没有任何动机，只是
kind of presenting the information as it
如实呈现了信息。
comments in that information about how
那条信息里有很多非常恶毒的评论，说
birth control can potentially be harming
避孕药可能会对
people that I don't believe the negative
人造成伤害。我不相信避孕药会有这些
side effects that can come with it all
副作用，
and I found them to not be true I had to
我发现这些说法都不属实。我不得不进行
do like a little soul searching to see
一番反思，看看
if they were true because I do that with
它们是否属实，因为我对
all the negative comments and I said no
所有负面评论都会这样做。我说，任何
birth control can have side effects just
避孕药都不可能有副作用，就像
like with any medication the reason why
任何药物一样。之所以会提到避孕药，
birth control maybe is being brought up
可能
is because this is a topic people are
是因为这是一个人们
very passionate about this is a topic
非常热衷的话题，也是一个
where doctors have discriminated in the
医生过去曾歧视过避孕药的话题，
past about so it's a bit more triggering
所以它更容易触动
to the emotional part of our brains but
我们大脑的情感部分。但是，
if we look at what's leading
如果我们看看美国导致
hospitalizations from a drug in the
住院的药物是什么——
United States Tylenol you don't see
泰诺，你不会看到
anyone uproar making YouTube videos that
有人在YouTube上发布视频，抗议
Tylenol is problematic what is Tylenol
泰诺有问题。泰诺是什么？
acetamin paracetamol for you a
对乙酰氨基酚，也就是
paracetamol
扑热息痛。是的，
Tylenol induced liver failure is skyh
泰诺导致肝衰竭的住院人数非常
high I'm sure we could pop up the
高，我相信我们可以把
statistics on screen but no one gets
统计数据显示在屏幕上，但没有人
upset about Tylenol because it's not
对泰诺感到愤怒，因为它…… 不会
emotionally triggering and that is true
引起情绪波动，这一点适用
for all of healthcare there's side
于所有医疗保健领域。
effects to taking
服用
medications so it's easy to only focus
药物会有副作用，所以很容易只关注其中的
on one part of that equation say well
一部分，比如“
doctors used to say this what about this
医生过去常这么说，那这个呢？
why did doctors say it what got them to
医生为什么这么说？是什么让他们这么
say it there and the idea of us getting
说的？”。
perfect never going to be true we're
我们永远不可能做到完美，我们总是基于
always working with incomplete
不完整的
information all of medicine is just our
信息。所有医学都只是我们
best
最好的
guess how many of you started thinking
猜测。你们当中有多少人是在30岁的时候开始考虑
about your long-term Health when you hit
自己的长期健康的？
30 for me this was a wake up moment of
对我来说，这是一个警醒的时刻，我
me thinking to myself okay I probably
心想：好吧，我可能
need to start paying a little bit more
需要开始更加
attention now I already felt a change
关注自己的健康了。30岁的时候，我已经感觉到
myself when I hit 30 with things like my
自己的一些变化，比如
metabolism my energy levels so this year
新陈代谢和精力水平。所以今年
is no different Zoe which is a company
也不例外。Zoe是一家
I've invested in but also a company that
我投资的公司，也是
are a sponsor of this podcast helps me
这个播客的赞助商。它帮助我
to make smarter food choices all based
做出更明智的食物选择，所有这些都
on their world leading science and my
基于他们世界领先的科学以及我
own test results if I'm ordering food I
自己的测试结果。如果我点外卖，我
know how to make my takeaway so much
知道如何让我的外卖更
smarter by adding things like a side of
健康，比如
vegetables to eat first or choosing the
先吃一份蔬菜，或者选择
option with the most fiber Zoe helps me
纤维含量最高的选项。Zoe帮助我
to make that choice it guides me and
做出这些选择。 它指导我、
coaches me it's my personalized
辅导我，它是我
nutrition coach that I have on me 24/7
24小时随身携带的私人营养教练。为了
and to help you start your Zoe journey
帮助你开启Zoe之旅，
and start making smarter food choices
做出更明智的食物选择，
I'm giving you guys 10% off when you
我特地为你们提供10%的折扣，
join Zoe now all you've got to do is use
现在加入Zoe即可享受优惠。只需
code ce10 at the checkout when you sign
在注册结账时使用代码ce10即可。
up enjoy and let me know how you get on
尽情享受吧，也请告诉我你的使用体验。
what about these animal studies a lot of
关于动物研究，很多
experts is from animal studies rats and
专家提出的研究都来自动物实验，比如老鼠之类的。是的，
things like that yes so that's where
所以
people like to skip steps the amount so
人们往往会忽略这些步骤。
Pharma is out for money right that's
制药公司是为了赚钱，对吧？这很
fair say that's their job they're trying
公平，这是他们的工作，他们试图
to create a return for their
为股东创造回报。
stockholders they try and pick research
他们会选择那些
to do that hopefully will drive the best
有望带来最大
profits 99% of the stuff that they start
利润的研究。他们最初基于
of animal studies 99% of it fails and
动物实验的初步成果开展的研究，99%都失败了，
they're only picking the top then you go
他们只会挑选出最好的。然后，
one step further once it works in animal
即使某种药物在动物
studies and Petri dishes and then it
实验和培养皿中有效，他们也会进一步进行
goes into human trials another 99% of it
人体试验，但99%的试验仍然会
fails so the idea that something has
失败。所以，认为某种药物有效的想法是错误的。
mechanistic value then Works in an in a
机制价值在于，它在
Petri dish then it works in an animal
培养皿中有效，然后在动物模型中也有效。
model for it to make all those steps is
要完成所有这些步骤，
so astronomically rare that it ends up
最终
working for the general
对普通
population the fact is that we shouldn't
人群有效，这种情况极其罕见。事实上，我们不应该直接
jump to from animal model to human
从动物模型跳到人体，
because 99% of that is going to
因为99%的尝试都会
fail so what are we saying then do we
失败。那么，我们到底想说什么？我们是不是应该
have to you know go back to just living
回归
like our ancestors lived and because you
祖先的生活方式？因为你
said earlier on that the world we live
之前说过，我们生活的世界
in is been more unnatural yeah so is the
越来越不自然。那么，解决
is the antidote for all of this stuff
所有这些问题的良方是什么？
we're talking about is it to go back to
回归人类本能吗？
being human and like we always say our
就像我们常说的，我们的
ancestors were well I think what we need
祖先……我认为我们需要
to look at is the evolution of humans
研究的是人类的进化
and the anthropology aspect of it
以及人类学方面，
because we can then better understand
因为这样我们才能更好地了解我们
ourselves now and why we're having
现在的自己，以及为什么我们会在
problems with this unnatural world right
这个不自然的世界中遇到问题。
so if you look at why anxiety was a a
所以，如果我们研究一下为什么焦虑在
survival benefit to us back then versus
过去对我们是一种生存优势，而
now in a safer World studying
现在在一个更安全的世界里它却可能成为很大的问题，那么研究
prehistoric cavemen humans would be
史前穴居人将会
beneficial but drawing conclusions from
很有帮助，我们可以从
their diets and potentially what they
他们的饮食以及其他方面得出结论。 如果你把
ate all men you're going to get into so
所有人都吃掉，你就会陷入
many fallacies and biases that the
很多谬误和偏见，导致
information is not going to be great and
信息质量不高，
not very applicable if you um if you
适用性也不强。如果你
could redesign Society in such a way
能重新设计社会，让它在
that it would be in your mind more
你看来对普通人来说
healthier more healthier for the for the
更健康，
average human you had to start from zero
你就必须从零开始。
so you're president of the United States
假设你是美国总统，
Trump doesn't get it Biden doesn't get
特朗普不明白，拜登不明白，
it Dr Mike gets it and you could really
迈克博士明白，而你真的可以
rewire Society what are the some of the
重塑社会，你会做出哪些
sort of macro Topline changes you would
宏观层面的改变？
make okay I'm
好吧，我先说说我的想法。
the table the first thing that I would
我会做的第一件事，也是
do and this is uh echoing one of the
呼应一位
authors and experts I I really enjoy
我非常喜欢听的作家和专家的观点（
listening to and he's actually coming on
他
my podcast soon Jonathan height I would
很快就会来我的播客节目），乔纳森·海特，我会让
schools I think that that much in the
学校里没有手机。我认为应该像
same way that we uh regulate addictive
我们监管
substances like cigarettes like vaping
香烟、电子烟、酒精等成瘾物质一样，
to start thinking about that for social
对社交
media and that's an unpopular thing to
媒体也采取类似的监管措施。
say but I think if you really look at it
我知道这么说不受欢迎，但如果你仔细想想，就会发现……
there's a lot of problems that can come
很多问题都由此而来，
from it very limited benefit for someone
对一个13岁的孩子来说，看这些图片的好处非常有限，
so I think some major changes need to be
所以我认为需要做出一些重大改变。
made uh in
嗯，在
schools you were voted in
学校里，你
2015 you know that's a long time ago 10
2015年被评为“最性感医生”，你知道，那是很久以前的事了，10
years ago in 2015 you were named people
年前的2015年。
alive I don't think I was voted I think
我不认为我是被投票选出来的，我想
they just nominated me well it's it is
他们只是提名了我。好吧，这确实是一件了不起的事，对吧？是的，就是这样。
something right yeah it is what it is um
嗯，
your relationships mhm what's your
你的感情生活……嗯，
relationship status if you're able to
如果你方便的话，你的感情状况如何？感情
share it relationship ship have been
生活一直
really tricky
很棘手。
um as a medical
作为一名医务
provider
人员，
you have to carry yourself with an air
你必须保持
of professionalism you have to make
专业的态度，你必须让
people feel comfortable in talking to
人们感到自在地与
you uh about very sensitive subjects so
你谈论非常敏感的话题。所以
I've been very careful to balance the
我一直非常小心地平衡着
world of showing my personal life to
在一定程度上展示我的个人生活
some degree and showing people and
和
reminding them that I'm human I too have
提醒人们注意安全之间的关系。 我也是人，我也有
relationships I to play sports I have a
感情生活，我也会运动，我有
family I have dogs but also not do it so
家庭，我养狗，但我不会过度沉迷于此，
much that it actually can cause harm in
以至于影响到
my clinical interactions so initially
我的临床互动。最初，
when I started social media I was very
当我开始使用社交媒体时，我非常
open about my relationships who I was
坦诚地分享我的感情生活，包括我的约会对象和
dating what my relationship status was
感情状态。
and I thought that I was under the firm
我当时
belief that there is no way this could
坚信这绝对不会
be detrimental and much in the same way
造成任何负面影响，就像
that I thought that reading every
我认为阅读每一条
negative comment can only be helpful boy
负面评论都只会对我有帮助一样。然而，事实证明
was I proven wrong not only does it
我错了。这不仅可能
cause harm to potentially the clinical
影响到我的临床
interactions it can cause harm with my
互动，还会影响到我的
online not dating patients that's not
线上粉丝。我指的不是和病人约会，不，不，我指的是
what I mean no no just a clinical
临床
interactions piece I mean well like you
互动方面的问题。我的意思是，
know if a patient is wondering who
如果病人好奇
you're dating or what you're dating that
你在和谁约会，或者你在做什么，这就会把
that's going to derail the conversation
话题
away from Health okay um the same way
从健康上转移开来。就像在
from social media from people listening
社交媒体上，人们本来应该关注的是
to Medical talking points to then
医学观点，结果却开始
talking about personal life um so before
谈论个人生活一样。所以，虽然
while I was being very open with it now
我以前很坦诚，但现在
I've kind of said my personal life to
我已经说过，我的个人生活在
some degree is my personal life when I
某种程度上就是我的个人生活。当我
begin sharing everyone will know about
开始分享时，所有人都会知道。 我以前到处走动，
it it'll be everywhere but now I tend to
但现在我倾向于更加注重
things for my personal life but the
个人生活，虽然也有一些私事，但
majority of it is an open book that's I
大部分时间我都坦诚相待。我很
was curious about your relationship
好奇你的感情
status because as someone who's so busy
状况，因为你既是
and a content creator and going through
内容创作者，又如此忙碌，还要经历
all of the things we described earlier
我们之前提到的
with your mental health and the feedback
心理健康问题、反馈等等，
and all of that sure how you manag to be
你是如何
successful in that realm as well yeah so
兼顾这些方面的呢？是的，就我目前的工作而言，
like in in doing what I do I I feel like
我觉得
I'm very busy because I'm involved in so
自己非常忙碌，因为我参与了
many different things but I feel like
很多不同的事情，但我觉得
everyone's busy you know you you make
每个人都很忙，你知道，你会抽出
time for what you're passionate about so
时间去做自己热爱的事情。
there was a period of time I was single
我曾经单身过
for a few years then I got into
几年，然后
relationships I got out of relationships
谈恋爱，
and it it really is if you meet the
又分手。如果你遇到了对的
right person and you want to dedicate
人，想要全身心投入，
your time to them you'll sacrifice
你就会有所牺牲。
something you know before I used to be
你知道，以前我晚上睡觉前会
all about watching sports like that was
看体育比赛，那是
my nighttime routine now I can't even
我的日常。现在我都记不清
tell you the last time I watched the
上次看
sporting event I've just been so busy
体育比赛是什么时候了，我太忙了，
like maybe the Ryan Garcia fight boxing
可能看过瑞恩·加西亚的拳击
match but um I don't I don't have the
比赛吧，但……我没看过。 我没
time for it because I've made sacrifices
时间做这件事，因为我为了
to do other things I'm passionate about
做其他我热爱的事情做出了牺牲。
and I think if your partner consistently
我觉得
that if your partner consistently says
如果你的伴侣总是说
they don't have time no matter how busy
没时间，不管他们有多忙，
they are you need to do a little
你都需要好好
evaluation and see is is that something
评估一下，看看这是否是
that they truly want or at least bring
他们真正想要的，或者至少应该和他们
conversation you're someone that strik
谈谈这个问题。你给我的印象是一个
quite philosophical and deep thinking in
在闲暇时间很爱思考、喜欢哲学思考的人，
their downtime M and probably spends a
M，你可能花了
lot of time thinking about bigger
很多时间思考
questions about life meaning purpose and
关于人生意义、目标等等的宏大问题，
all of those things is that a accurate
是这样吗？
B what are those big things that you're
B，你在思考的那些宏大问题具体是什么？
considering in your mind um it's
嗯，这很
accurate but not big picture big
准确，但不是那种宏观的、宏大的
philosophical questions it's
哲学问题，
more I'm deep thinking from an
我更多的是从内省的角度进行深度思考，
of running back every day what could I
每天回顾自己，思考我还能
have done
做得更好吗？
better what can I improve on uh what
我能改进什么？
should I think about for the future how
我应该为未来思考什么？
can I grow from today so I spend a lot
我如何才能从今天开始成长？我花了很多
of time doing that and that's not
时间做这些，这并不是我小时候就养成的习惯，
was a kid I remember this very vividly
我对此记忆犹新。
in high school age 13 being very awkward
13岁那年，我上高一，感觉很尴尬。
freshman year of high school um talking
嗯，
to girls at my class and then coming
在班上跟女生说话，然后
home and sleeping in my bed and as I'm
回家躺在床上睡觉，
going to sleep thinking oh my God what
临睡前总会想：天哪，
should I have said to look cool maybe I
我当时应该说什么才显得酷？也许我
should have just stayed quiet like those
应该像电影里那些酷哥一样保持沉默。
those scenarios throughout the day and
这些场景我整天都在反复琢磨。虽然
while that was silly when I was 13 now
13岁的时候觉得这很傻，但现在
as a doctor I play back my patient
作为一名医生，我会回想自己和病人的
encounters and think about what I could
互动，思考
do better in that communication sense I
在沟通方面哪些地方可以做得更好。我也会
play back my podcast interviews in my
回想自己录制的播客采访，
head and think about what I could do
思考哪些地方可以做得更好。
better so I'm constantly thinking about
所以我一直在想这些，
that and again not by choice it just
而且这并非出于我的本意，只是自然而然地
kind of happening in my mind and that's
发生在我的脑海里。
where the anxiety stems from I guess um
我想，焦虑大概就是从这里开始的。
the anxiety can creep up there if you
如果你
feel like you're not improving or your
觉得自己没有进步，或者
progress is stagnating like um the idea
进展停滞不前，焦虑就会悄悄滋生。比如，
that I told you I wasn't exercising a
我之前跟你说过我运动量不大，
lot I start ruminating and thinking oh
我就开始反复思考：
my God you haven't been exercising in so
天哪，你这么久没运动了，身体肯定
long now you're going to not be healthy
不行了。万一
what if people online start thinking
网上的人开始这么想怎么办？
that oh that's not a healthy thing to do
哦，这可不是…… 这样做很健康，
and you could start catastrophizing very
但你很容易就会开始灾难化思考。
easy this is what our human Minds do and
这是我们人类思维的运作方式，所以
that's why C BT cognitive behavioral
认知行为
therapy one of the more popular forms of
疗法（CBT）——一种比较流行的
evidence-based therapy is taking those
循证疗法——就是要反驳这些
cognitive distortions those
认知扭曲，那些
catastrophized black or white labeling
灾难化的非黑即白的标签化
thoughts and just talking back to them
想法。比如，
saying how true is that that if you had
如果你
all A's on your tests and then you got
考试全是A，然后得了
one C that you're a failure how true is
一个C，你就失败了吗？
it that if you don't exercise for three
如果你三个月不锻炼，
months that means you're an out of shape
你就是个身材走样的邋遢鬼了吗？
slob and you have to talk back to them
你必须反驳这些想法。
so doctors are not immune to cognitive
所以医生也无法避免认知
distortions I always wonder with doctors
扭曲。我总是好奇，医生在
when you're dealing with like People's
面对人们的
Health and their outcomes which
健康和治疗结果时，这些结果
sometimes are positive and sometimes not
有时是积极的，有时是
positive how that can sit on your
消极的，这会给你带来怎样的压力？
shoulders and how you can take that home
你会如何把这些带回家？
with you because you must deal with a
因为你必须面对
lot of people that are no longer here
很多已经离世的人。是的，当然。
yeah for sure um especially when I would
尤其是我作为
be a resident working in the ICU where
住院医生在
an intensive care unit patients are the
重症监护室工作时，那里的病人病情最
sickest so mo more likely for them to
重，生命垂危的风险也更高，
lose their lives you're having
你还要
conversations with family members about
和他们的家人沟通。 成员们讨论
discontinuing CPR about signing certain
停止心肺复苏术，以及签署某些
papers to say that we're not going to
文件，声明我们不再
give more medical care we're only going
提供更多医疗护理，只
to focus on comfort as opposed to
专注于舒适护理而非
treatment and those conversations are
治疗。这些对话
not easy conversations and the way that
并不容易，而
I've approached them is with unbiased
我处理这些对话的方式是秉持客观公正的原则，坦诚相告。
to know what I know I'm explaining to
我会解释我的想法，让你们知道我所知道的，
you why I think what I think now you
然后告诉你们
tell me what you'd like to do and
你们的想法。
ultimately it gives
最终，这能以一种积极的方式赋予
patients a sense of responsibility in a
患者责任感，让
good way where it empowers them or
他们或
empowers their family members to make
他们的家人有能力做出
the right choice and the right choice is
正确的选择。而正确的选择
not clear two people can make different
并非一目了然，两个人可以做出不同的
choices and they both be right choices
选择，而且都可能是正确的选择。医疗
um Healthcare is as much art as it is a
保健就像艺术一样，它既是
science so so two doctors can see the
科学，也是艺术。所以，两位医生可以接诊
same patient and recommend two different
同一位患者，并推荐两种不同的
treatments and not be wrong is there was
治疗方案，而他们的建议都不会出错。
there a hardest day when you think back
回想
over your medical career was there a
你的医疗生涯，有没有哪一天是你经历过的最艰难的？
hardest day in your practice
在你的行医过程中，有没有哪一天是最难熬的？没有
no nothing that specifically jumps out I
特别突出的。我
think it's it's how it wears on you from
认为最难熬的是工作时间的
a perspective of just length
长短和
of the amount of administrative work you
大量的行政事务带来的疲惫感。 你
have to do the amount of time you want
必须完成的工作，是你想要
to spend with the patient versus what
花在病人身上的时间和
you're given um the ability of
你实际拥有的时间之间的差距。还有那种
helplessness where you can't fully help
无力感，
a patient no matter how much you want to
无论你多么想帮助病人，你都无法完全帮到他们。
when you know if a patient does a
你知道如果病人接受某种
specific treatment you know they'll get
治疗，他们会
better but they're not interested in it
好转，但他们却不感兴趣，
or are being deceived or influenced in a
或者被欺骗或影响，
way where they're not going down the
没有走上
right path those really really drain me
正确的道路。这些真的让我精疲力竭，
because I I think about those at night
因为我晚上会想，
of how can I be more effective so I can
怎样才能更有效率，才能
help my patient come to the right
帮助病人得出正确的
conclusion or at least help them make a
结论，或者至少帮助他们做出
decision that is actively not
不会
detrimental to their health your mission
损害自身健康的决定。你
at the moment to really help to myth
目前的使命是帮助人们破除谣言，揭露与
it relates to health care and advice is
医疗保健和建议相关的虚假信息，这
that driven in part because as a doctor
部分原因是否在于，作为一名医生，
you're seeing the consequences firsthand
你亲眼目睹了
of information your patients are
病人
bringing to you that is patently false
带给你的那些明显错误、不
or untrue or doesn't isn't quote unquote
实或未经
proven um and then you're basically
证实的信息所造成的后果，然后你基本上要
arguing with them about that or or
和他们争论这些？这就是原因吗？是的，这就是
yeah that's why I started social media
我开始做这件事的原因。 社交媒体
because I was having a very similar
让我意识到，
conversation with the 30 patients that I
我每天要和30位病人进行类似的对话，
saw in a day and I was like wow I got to
我当时就想，哇，我必须把
tell the world this so they can all know
这些告诉全世界，让大家都知道
this information so that they all don't
这些信息，这样他们就不会上当受骗了。比如，
fall VI them to these scams where they
他们
think doctor I had $100 this month to
以为医生说：“我这个月有100美元可以
spend on my health and I bought this
用来保健，我买了这
thing I bought these two smoothies and I
玩意儿，买了这两瓶果昔，我
thought this is the answer this is going
以为这就是答案，这肯定能帮到
to help me right this says it helps with
我，对吧？它说可以治疗
cancer and
癌症，但事实并非如此。”正是
those conversations over and over again
这些反复的对话
it's what drove the passion to being on
激发了我对
social media and now I think about
社交媒体的热情。现在我对
medicine differently than I did when I
医学的看法和刚入行时截然不同。
first started I used to think medicine
我以前认为医学
is doctor and patient now I view it more
就是医生和病人之间的关系，现在我更多地从
in a public health sense where my impact
公共卫生的角度来看待它。我
on social media goes so much further
在社交媒体上的影响力远远超出了与
than patient interactions or viewer
病人或观众的
interactions where now I can influence
互动，我现在甚至可以影响
policy had a medical emergency on a
政策。有一次我在
flight and they made that call is there
飞机上遇到突发疾病，他们问我
a doctor on board and I was faced with a
机上有没有医生。
moment like okay do I volunteer do I
我当时很纠结，
just stay quiet I don't know what to do
不知道该怎么办，
but I volunteered and it turned out
但我还是主动请缨了。结果证明，
after some investigation that a young
之后…… 调查显示，一位年轻
gentleman was going into anaphylactic
男士出现了过敏性
shock his throat was closing up to it an
休克，他的喉咙因为
allergy and I wasn't worried I said
过敏而闭合。我当时并不担心，就问他：“
where where's your EpiPen he said I
你的肾上腺素自动注射器（EpiPen）呢？” 他说：“我
don't have one I didn't even know I had
没有，我甚至不知道自己有
this allergy so I asked the pilot can we
这种过敏症。” 于是我问飞行员：“我们能
land pilot says well it's an hour and a
降落吗？” 飞行员说：“
half back to Canada and an hour to
飞回加拿大需要一个半小时，飞到
Portugal some Island in Portugal that's
葡萄牙的某个岛屿也需要一个小时，时间
not enough time his throat's closing
不够。” 他的喉咙正在闭合，
he's going to die in five
五分钟内就会死亡。
minutes so I'm like what can I do so I
我当时就想：“我该怎么办？” 我
opened the plan's emergency kit thinking
打开了飞机上的急救箱，心想
there's going to be some epinephrine in
里面应该会有肾上腺素
there or an EpiPen and there's no
或者EpiPen，结果发现没有
EpiPen and I'm like okay what do I do
EpiPen。我心想：“好吧，现在怎么办？” 在
the Atlantic Ocean so there's nothing to
大西洋上空没有网络，所以没法上网
Google but um finding that there is
搜索。但我后来发现，
epinephrine which is the same medicine
肾上腺素和EpiPen里的药物成分相同，只是配方和
dosage for a cardiac arrest so when
剂量不同，是用于心脏骤停的。所以，当
someone's heart stops we also give the
有人心脏停止跳动时，
same medicine if they're Flatline if
如果心跳停止，我们也会使用同样的药物。
they have a specific Rhythm to try and
为了尝试重启心脏，我们需要一种特定的节律，
restart the heart so it's a much thicker
所以用的
needle much longer not those cute little
针头更粗更长，不是那种可爱的小
EpiPen needles that just go into the
针头，可以扎进
side of your thigh and I said okay well
大腿侧面。我说，好吧，
I need to do some rough calculations
我需要粗略计算一下，
here and just uh guesstimate here
估算一下，
because otherwise he's going to lose his
否则他会没命的。就在
cabin we take off his pants we uh inject
头等舱里，我们脱下他的裤子，用
them with this huge needle he's
这根粗大的针头给他注射，他
screaming there's like a little bit of
尖叫起来，有点
blood coming out I inject the medicine
血渗出来了。我注射了药物，
I'm praying that it's working and fast
祈祷它能起作用。快
forward that story uh I stayed with him
进到故事的结尾，我陪了他
for eight hours for the rest of that
八个小时，
flight until he landed we didn't need to
直到他降落。我们不需要
divert I checked his blood pressure and
改道。我
pulse every 15 to 30 minutes and uh we
每隔15到30分钟就给他量一次血压和脉搏，我们
saved his
救了他的
life and you think that would be the end
命。你可能会觉得故事到此结束，
of it you're like look at that I did my
你会想，瞧，我完成了我的
doctor job and that's it but I went and
医生工作，这就完了。但我把
told that St Story on YouTube got almost
这个故事上传到YouTube，
10 million views if not more now I don't
点击量接近1000万，甚至更多，现在我不
know what it's at and um the Senate
知道是多少了。 参议院
Majority Leader Chuck Schumer calls from
多数党领袖查克·舒默从
his office or his office calls and says
他的办公室打来电话，说：“
hey uh I'd like to get epipens on planes
嘿，我想在飞机上配备肾上腺素自动注射器（EpiPen）。
can you stand with us and tell us your
你能和我们一起向媒体讲述一下你的
story to the
故事吗？”是的，
media yes we tell the story we call on
我们讲述了这个故事，我们呼吁联邦航空
the FAA to make these changes and now
管理局（FAA）做出这些改变。现在，大约
70% of planes I don't know what the
70%的飞机——我不知道
exact number is but something like 70%
确切的数字是多少——都
of planes have epip pens on board that
配备了肾上腺素自动注射器，这样就
will never have to happen again that's
不会再发生类似的事情了。这真是
incredible and that's the power of
太棒了！这就是
social media that people don't talk
社交媒体的力量，人们很少谈论它，这就是
about that's Public Health that's
公共卫生，它正在
helping people that aren't even needing
帮助那些甚至还不需要帮助的人。这就是
medicine I like to think about now well
我喜欢思考的那种医疗方式。现在，
you have a half a body lying over there
你看，角落里躺着半具尸体。
in the corner so in the in the sake of
为了
helping people using social media um I
帮助那些使用社交媒体的人，我
asked you if you could bring a I don't
问你能不能带一个——我甚至不
even know what to call that it looks
知道该怎么称呼它——它看起来
like a half a mannequin or something a
像个半截人体模型，或者别的什么——人体模型，
mannequin it's a mannequin um because
它就是个人体模型。因为
early in my life I got told that
我从小就被告知，
learning learning the skill of CPR is
学习…… 心肺复苏术是
life-saving things that I could learn
我能学到的最简单的、可能救命的技能之一，
because you never know and I've got
因为你永远不知道会发生什么。
people in my family that died of various
我的家人中有人死于各种
cardiovascular related um conditions
心血管疾病，比如
heart attacks and things like that and
心脏病发作等等。
so I would love to learn again again
所以我很想再次学习。
this is probably not an official
这可能不是官方
certification to learn the basics of CPR
认证，但可以学习心肺复苏术的基础知识
and how to keep someone alive in such a
以及如何在紧急情况下挽救他人的生命。
situation um could jack could you bring
杰克，你能把那个……
the the what should we call him we'll
我们该叫他……就叫
call him off Mike yeah we we'll call him
他小迈克吧？好的，我们叫他……
uh baby
小
Mike so I'm curious before we do any
迈克。在我们开始任何指导之前，我很好奇，
kind of instruction on it what do you
你
know thus far about CPR and all wrong
目前对心肺复苏术了解多少？所有错误
answers are acceptable here um you push
答案都可以接受。嗯，你要按压
on the chest roughly around the top of
胸部，大概在
the rib cage and then you blow into the
肋骨上方的位置，然后对着嘴吹气，反复这样做
again until they come back to life okay
直到他们恢复呼吸。好的，
do you know what the reason of doing CPR
你知道做心肺复苏术的原因是什么吗？嗯，问得好。这
is H that's a very good and it's not a
不是个
trick question I'm just genuinely
陷阱问题，我只是真的很
curious because I like to know where
好奇，因为我想知道
we're starting from and no one knows
我们从哪里开始。顺便说一句，没人知道
this by the way this is why I do what I
这一点。这就是我做这件事的原因。
do so this is not it's something to do
这
with keeping oxygen flowing around the
跟保持
body through the blood you're right on
血液循环有关，你说得对。
target okay so the purpose of CPR is if
好的，心肺复苏的目的是，如果
you find someone who's unconscious not
你发现有人失去意识、停止
breathing is pulseless that means their
呼吸、没有脉搏，这意味着他们的
heart's not beating that means
心脏停止跳动，从
clinically they're dead so anything you
临床上讲，他们已经死亡。所以你在
do here can only potentially hurt help
这里做的任何事都只会造成潜在的伤害，帮助
can't hurt right cuz the person is
不会造成伤害，对吧？因为这个人
already dead so by doing proper CPR what
已经死了。所以，正确的心肺复苏术
you're doing is you're compressing the
是通过
chest chest compressions to squeeze the
胸外按压来挤压心脏，
heart which has some blood in it to
心脏里还有一些血液，可以把
circulate the blood throughout the body
血液循环到全身，血液里还有
that still has some residual oxygen in
一些残余的氧气，可以把
it to deliver oxygen to the vital organs
氧气输送到重要器官。
so you're not actually saving someone's
所以，你做心肺复苏术实际上并不是在拯救
life by doing CPR you're buying them
生命，而是在为他们争取
time the purpose of doing CPR is to
时间。做心肺复苏术的目的是为急救人员和紧急救援人员争取
allow time for First Response ERS to
时间，让他们
arrive to then give Advanced cardiac
赶到现场提供高级心脏
life support oh okay and that's why the
生命支持。哦，好的。这就是为什么
first step of doing CPR has nothing to
做心肺复苏的第一步
do with the person and has everything to
与这个人无关，而与
do with calling for help okay so I call
呼叫救援有关。好的，所以我要打电话给急救
the First Responders or because that
人员，因为那样会……所以
would so ideally you never want to do
理想情况下，你永远不应该做
anything that will distract you from
任何会分散他们注意力的事情。
starting chest compressions because the
开始进行胸外按压，因为
faster you can get to doing chest
越早开始
compressions the better are your
按压，
outcomes so tell someone else to call
结果就越好。所以，
ideally if you're alone obviously that's
如果你独自一人，最好告诉别人打电话。当然，这种情况
not happening but you can't just say out
不太可能发生。但你不能直接大声喊“
into the open hey someone call 911
嘿，有人打911吗？”，
because what happens everyone assumes
因为结果会是大家都以为是
the other person calls no one calls this
别人打的，结果却没人打。这种情况
happened with many medical emergencies
在很多医疗紧急情况下都会发生，
and it's terrible when it happens
而且非常可怕。
there's actually criminal cases about
实际上，甚至还有相关的刑事案件。
that someone screaming for help and
有人呼救，
everyone assuming the other neighbor
大家都以为是邻居打的，
would call and then no one ends up
结果却没人
calling so you have to say Hey you in
打。所以，你必须说：“嘿，
the blue shirt you and the pink hat you
穿蓝衬衫的，戴粉帽子的，你
call 911 and they will call 911 and you
打911。”他们会打的。然后，你要
immediately start pushing hard and fast
立即开始用力快速地按压
in the center of the chest one hand on
胸部中央，一只手叠在
top of the other when you say center of
另一只手上。你说
the chest you mean in between the pecs
胸部中央，是指胸肌之间，对吧？
correct okay so right in between the
好的，就在
pecs one hand on top of the other on top
胸肌之间，一只手叠在另一只手上。
of the other what if I break whole body
如果我按压得太紧，整个身体都受伤了怎么办？
doesn't person's dead so I can go as
人就死了。所以我可以根据
because in order to compress the heart
情况用力按压。按压深度要达到两英寸（约5厘米），这意味着要用力按压。 要按压心脏，
you need to go 2 in deep and two inch
你需要按压到胸腔中央，也就是胸肌之间的位置，
deep is pretty 5 cm deep so one hand on
大约5厘米深。一只手叠在
top of the other push hard and fast in
另一只手上，用力快速地按压
the center of the chest in between the
胸肌之间的位置，
pecs and you're doing that until help
直到救援人员
arrives okay so you see how you're uh
赶到。你看，你现在的情况和
much like most people who are in really
大多数
good shape you're using your triceps
体能很好的人一样，都在用肱三头肌发力。
yeah try doing that for more than two
是的，试试连续按压超过两
minutes you will fade no matter what
分钟，无论你的体能有多好，你都会感到疲惫。
good shape you're in in fact when we're
事实上，在
in the hospitals the way that we do this
医院里，我们每次
is maximum two minutes at a time and
最多按压两分钟，
then we tap out and get the next person
然后就停止，让下一个人接手，
in because it's so tiring the way to Max
因为这非常累人。要尽可能地用
full body weight correct and you hear
全身的重量按压，对吧？你听到“咔哒”
the click that means you're doing it to
一声，就表示你按压到了
the correct depth and that way you will
正确的深度。这样你就不会那么容易
get less tired and you'll be able to do
疲劳，也能坚持更
that for longer periods of time so that
长时间。听到“咔哒”一声，就
click means I'm hitting the heart for
表示我用
this little device yes I had to go down
这个小装置按压到了心脏。是的，我必须按压到
a long way away I had to go down so far
很深的程度，我平时根本
that I would never have naturally done
不可能按到这么深，
that to somebody I would have thought
我以为
that I was going to do more damage
我还能按得更深。 正是
correct and because of that fear that
因为这种恐惧，导致
people have we unfortunately have worse
人们在现场发生心脏骤停时，不幸地造成了更糟糕的
outcomes with people who have cardiac
后果。
arrest in the field and in fact most
事实上，大多数
cardiac arrests meaning heart stopping
心脏骤停（即心脏停止跳动）
happen not in hospital settings they
并非发生在医院，而是发生
happen in community settings they happen
在社区，发生
on the street at dinners with our loved
在街头，发生在与
ones and the important point to remember
亲人共进晚餐时。这里需要记住的重要一点是，
here this isn't what you do for someone
这不是针对那些
who's talking and is having a heart
还能说话、正在心脏病发作的人的处理方法，而是
attack this is for cardiac arrest
针对心脏骤停的情况。心脏骤停时，患者
they're not talking they're not moving
不会说话，不会动弹，也
they're not breathing because if they're
不会呼吸。因为如果他们还能
talking that means they have a
说话，就意味着他们还有
pulse because I've seen in some videos
脉搏。我在网上看到一些视频，
online like someone's trying to talk or
有人试图说话或
moving around are doing chest I'm like
移动，却在进行胸外按压。我心想，
no stop he's doing chest compression but
不行，停！他只是在做胸外按压。但
if they're pulseless if they're not
如果他们没有脉搏，没有
breathing they're unconscious start
呼吸，已经失去意识，那么
hands only CPR after calling for help I
在呼救后，应该立即开始徒手心肺复苏。
can't I really want to emphasize how
我真的想强调一下，
hard I had to push down then it wasn't
我必须用多大的力气按压，这
just like pushing on the surface I had
不仅仅是按压表面，我必须
to put all my weight and shove down on
用尽全身的重量，用力按压
the chest and you know that insecurity
胸部。你知道，
about the amount of pressure that you
你刚才提到的那种对按压力度的不确定感。
outcomes for women who have a cardiac
对于心脏骤停的女性来说，后果甚至更严重。
arrest because people are afraid of
逮捕是因为人们害怕
pushing in between breasts ah if the
在胸部之间按压。啊，如果
Responders ared because you bought them
急救人员赶到时，因为你为他们争取了
time do it it's not fair that women are
时间，就能挽救生命，那就去做吧。女性
bystandard because of their bodies I
因为身体原因而更难得到标准的CPR，这不公平。我
thought because I think again because
以为，因为
I've watched so many movies that when
我看过很多电影，电影里说当
you start doing the CPR the person comes
你开始做CPR时，病人就会
back to life it can happen Okay CU I
复活，这是有可能发生的。好吧，CU，我
thought that's what you were doing I
以为你做的就是复活他们，我
thought you were like bringing them back
以为你是在让他们
to life that's what if that's the notion
复活。如果
that some people have and that's why I
有些人有这种想法，那该怎么办？所以我
want them to make sure that you're not
想让他们明白，你实际上并不是在复活他们，而是在为
you're buying them time and circulating
他们争取时间，循环
the residual oxygen so that help can
残余氧气，以便救援人员
arrive to try and restart the heart how
赶到并尝试重新启动心脏。
long do you have to do what's the
你需要做多久？
longest you've had to do CPR on someone
你做过最长的CPR是多久？最后病人活了下来。
Surviving I've been in um double digits
我以前做过十几次，都是
before for young patients um because
给年轻病人做的。因为
young patients we will like if you have
年轻病人……就像你遇到的
a patient who's elderly who's in the ICU
老年病人，在ICU里。 如果病人已经病得很重，而
the odds are that you'll bring them back
我们却不得不停止抢救，那么他们复活的几率显然
are obviously very low but even if you
非常低。即使我们成功
will bring them back to life they're
抢救，他们的
going to be in a worse quality of life
生活质量也会
than they already were so many times we
比之前更差。很多时候，我们会在进行
actually have a conversation as the CPR
心肺复苏的同时
is ongoing with the families explaining
与家属沟通，解释
that and saying that this is not
这一点，并说明这样做并无
beneficial that even if we bring them
益处。即使我们成功
back they might be in a worse State and
抢救，他们的状况也可能更糟，
that we don't recommend it we actually
因此我们不建议这样做。我们
have scores and guidelines that we can
有一些评分和指南可以
discuss with patients about statistics
与病人讨论相关的统计数据。
on this but when someone's very young
但是，如果病人非常年轻，比如一个
let's say you have a 20-year-old who has
20岁的年轻人突发
an unusual Cardiac Arrest we would fight
罕见的心脏骤停，我们会尽力抢救更
much longer because they have an
长时间，因为
opportunity to heal once we bring them
一旦他们恢复健康，就有机会康复。
back so it's very dependent on a on a
所以，这很大程度上取决于
specific situation and you had to have
具体情况。
that exact same conversation when
当
someone was operate when treating your
有人接受手术时，你必须和
mother of yep I that was the
家属进行同样的沟通。是的，我经历过这样的
conversation that was my first
对话，那是我第一次
interaction with that kind of
接触到那种
environment I actually remember um when
环境。我还记得当时
I
我
was in the the room and the alarms were
在房间里，警报声响起，
going off and the residents or the
住院医生或
doctors were doing CPR and I called it
医生正在进行心肺复苏，我喊了一声“……”
off I remember the next time I heard
我记得 艾伯，我下次听到
those alarms was during my training in a
那些警报声是在我参加
patient simulation
病人模拟
lab and that was like the first moment I
实验室培训的时候。那是我第一次经历
flashback where a sound brought back a
闪回，声音唤起了某种
feeling where that sound of those alarms
感觉，那些警报声
brought me back to how I felt and how
让我回想起当时的感受，那种
uncomfortable I felt I've never felt
难受的感觉。我以前从未有过这种感觉。
you must have had that sound a lot since
从那以后，你肯定经常听到那种声音吧？
then oh yeah and I've had some difficult
哦，是的，也因此我
conversations with my fellow colleagues
和同事们进行过一些艰难的谈话。
because of it I remember very vividly
我清楚地记得
when my mom passed away we were in the
我母亲去世那天，我们在
waiting room waiting for documentation
候诊室等着
forms to sign and I came out to check
签署文件，我出去
and see if they're finishing up and some
看看他们是不是快办完了，一些
of the nurses and doctors I don't even
护士和医生——我甚至不
know what medical professionals they
知道他们是什么医务人员——
little work area in the back now where
在后面的小工作区里笑着，那里
they were patient facing but hearing
他们面对着病人。听到
those laughs got me so angry how could
他们的笑声让我非常生气，怎么会
anyone laugh during a time like this but
有人在这种情况下笑呢？但
then I had to remind myself these are
我不得不提醒自己，他们
people too these are people who are
也是人，他们
losing patients every day and if they
每天都在失去病人，如果他们像
took the loss the way that I'm taking
我一样承受失去亲人的痛苦，
this loss they wouldn't last they
他们也坚持不下去，他们就
wouldn't be able to help my mom or other
无法帮助我的母亲或其他
moms so I had to remind myself about
母亲了。所以我必须提醒自己。 我自己也经历过类似的事情，
that but what my take away from it was
但我从中得到的感悟是，
when I saw co-residents of mine maybe
当我看到我的同事们在
writing their notes after someone's
记录一位病人的
family passed away and I see the family
家人去世后的情况时，我看到家属就
in earshot and they're talking about
在附近，他们谈论着当天的事情，
their day or they're laughing or they're
或者说着笑声、
giggling or saying some kind of joke not
窃笑，或者开着
related to the situation I I just I
与此事无关的玩笑，我
don't correct them that's not my place
没有纠正他们，因为那不是我应该
to do I just share my story of how I
做的。我只是分享了我的
felt and I thought it created a really
感受。我认为这是一个
good learning
很好的学习
opportunity Dr Mike we have a closing
机会。迈克医生，我们这个播客有个结束的
tradition on this podcast where the last
传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，但
guest not knowing who they leaving it
并不知道问题会留给谁。
for if you could go back to a pivotal
如果你可以回到
moment in your life
人生中的一个关键时刻
and make a different
并做出不同的
decision what would that moment be and
选择，你会选择哪个时刻？
why I think about the social isolation
为什么？我想到了
and loneliness that you described that I
你描述的那种社交孤立和孤独感，那是我
felt when I lost my
失去
mom and how I isolated myself from my
母亲后感受到的。直到今天，我仍然把自己与同学隔离开来。
300 students in my class or
我们班有大约300名学生，
so I didn't make a lot of friends in
我没有交到多少朋友，事实上，
friends and I was not
我一个朋友也没有。我完全不
involved um I was fully disconnected
参与班级活动，我
from my class and I I think it's because
与班级完全脱节。我想这都是因为
of what I was going through at that time
我当时的情况。 当时我经历了很多，
and I wish that
我真希望
um I either reached out for support from
我当时能向学校寻求帮助，
or created conversations amongst my
或者和
classmates because the friendships that
同学们多聊聊，因为
they've created have lasted to now this
他们建立的友谊一直延续至今，这都
is over a DEC decade um people got
超过十年了。
married in those classes they've created
同学们结婚了，他们结下了
lifelong friends and I feel like because
终生的友谊。我觉得，因为
I moved away and I was two hours away
我搬走了，
from the school I wasn't a part of it
离学校有两个小时的车程，所以我没能融入其中。
and I feel like that has significantly
我觉得这极大地
impacted the number of friendships I
影响了我至今的友谊数量。
I do have are my close friends from high
我的朋友大多是高中时的挚友，
school maybe some from college but
也许还有一些大学的朋友，但
almost none from medical school and I
几乎没有医学院的朋友。我
feel like that's a really really big
觉得这真的是一个非常大的
missed opportunity do you feel
遗憾。你会感到
lonely yeah sometimes for
孤独吗？当然，有时候会。
sure but I think that's a byproduct of
但我认为这是
society these days and my work adds to
当今社会的副产品，我的工作也加剧了
that as well Dr Mike thank you so much
这种情况。迈克医生，非常
thank you for all of the work you do and
感谢您所做的一切，以及
the way you do it um you're the one of
您做事的方式。您是
the most accessible voices on the
互联网上最容易接触到的
internet as it relates to medical
医学
information and I say accessible
信息提供者之一。我特意强调“容易接触”，
intently because um sometimes doctors
因为有时候医生
can be a little bit um
会有点……
exclusive they're too smart and they
高高在上，他们太聪明了，他们
don't really let us in but I think
不太…… 让我们进来吧，但我认为
you're both confronting disinformation
你们都在以
in a really honest fair balanced way but
非常诚实、公平、平衡的方式对抗虚假信息，同时
at the same time you're providing
你们也以
information in such an accessible way
如此易于理解的方式提供信息。
and um you've drawn a tremendous
你们
audience to you across YouTube and your
在YouTube、播
podcast and across your socials and
客、社交媒体以及
everywhere else and it's there's no
其他所有平台上都吸引了大量的受众。
doubt in my mind that you've not just
我毫不怀疑，你们不仅
saving the lives in your practice every
每天在自己的诊所里拯救生命，
day but you're saving hundreds of
还在拯救
thousands of lives you'll never meet but
成千上万你们永远不会遇到的生命，而且
also you're improving so many lives
你们也在改善许多人的生活，
because your health helping us to
因为你们的健康信息帮助我们
navigate towards um better information
更好地获取信息，
or a better way to think about the
或者更好地思考
information we receive and I'm on that
我们接收到的信息。我也在这条
Journey too I'm doing my very best to
路上，我正在尽我所能地去理解
try and navigate that and as someone
它。作为一个每周都要
that sits here with a lot of experts
和很多专家（这
which is your lowest criteria of like
是你们对
acceptable evidence experts and medical
可接受证据的最低标准，包括专家和医疗
practitioners and I'm doing this two
从业者）坐在一起的人，我
three times a week sometimes there's
每周要这样做两三次，有时经常会遇到相互
often conflicting information um I'm I
矛盾的信息。我总是很难决定
always struggle with how to present that
如何呈现这些
information because on one hand you
信息，因为一方面，你
don't want to censor people because that
不想审查人们，因为那
assumes that I know what's right but on
假设我知道什么是对的，但
the other hand you feel a sense
另一方面，你又觉得 有
responsibility that the the platform
责任感，确保
you're creating is is not doing any harm
你创建的平台不会造成任何伤害。
and I think that's the first kind of
我认为这是所有
produce content is doing no harm so Mike
内容创作者的首要原则——不作恶。迈克，
you're a prime example of someone that I
你就是我
see doing no harm and a lot of good in
见过的不作恶、为世界带来诸多益处的典范。非常
the world so thank you so much for your
感谢你，我非常
very much appreciate you saying that it
感激你的肯定，这对我意义重大。
means a lot you know a lot of days uh me
你知道，很多时候，我
and my team my small team will sit in
和我的团队——我的小团队——坐在
front of the camera and talk and forget
镜头前聊天，却忘记了我们创作的内容会对世界产生怎样的
the implications and the outcomes that
影响和后果。正是像你刚才说的这些
continually drives Us by reminders like
提醒，不断激励着我们。
what you just said so I appreciate you
所以我很感谢你的鼓励，请
saying please keep going I know it's
继续努力。我知道这
difficult some sometimes and I know
有时很困难，也知道有些
people do are very vicious I've been on
人非常恶毒，我
life but I think um you know that I
一生中大部分时间都深受其害。但我认为，你明白
don't have to tell you this but you know
我的意思，我不必赘述，但你也知道，
that the net impact of your mission is
你的使命所带来的最终影响是
so unbelievable it's so you'll never see
如此巨大，你永远无法亲眼目睹，你永远无法
it you'll never meet the people the
见到那些人，那些
families the father the mother the
家庭，那些父亲、母亲、
grandfather but I just wish you could
祖父，但我…… 真希望你能明白，
because I because I think if you could
因为我觉得如果你能
see the the net impact it would put all
看到最终的影响，就能把所有
of that stuff um in in perspective where
那些事都放在正确的角度看待。
it should be so Mike thank you thank you
所以，迈克，谢谢你，
appreciate you having me on
谢谢你邀请我上
[Music]
[音乐]节目。